<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Koding University</title>
  <atom:link
    href="//learn.koding.com/rss.xml"
    rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>//learn.koding.com</link>
  <description>
    An education center focused around the online development environment
    Koding.
  </description>
  <language>en</language>
  
  <item>
    <title>Updating the OS (and other packages) your VM</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/upgrading-your-vm</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-12-21T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/upgrading-your-vm</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This guide will walk you through the process of upgrading the OS, Kernel and core packages on your Koding VM.
We will walk through the following steps:

Updating the packages (strictly update the current packages)
Updating the distribution/OS (install newly released packages)

So depending on your need, you can do 1) or 2) or both.
Note: Even though we have tested upgrading the VM, some updates may render your VM inaccessible so
please proceed only if you know what you are doing. If you run into problems, you can always 
re-init your VM or send us a request via support@koding.com.
  A few prep commands To get started, log into your Koding account and check what version of the OS and Kernel that
you currently have by typing the following command in Terminal:
uname -rv
this should return you something like this:
3.13.0-29-generic #53-Ubuntu SMP Wed Jun 4 21:00:20 UTC 2014
Make a note of the kernel version, you can reference it later to ensure that the kernel update
worked.
You should also take a note of available disk space before you begin to ensure that you have adequate
space for all the updates. To get available disk space, type this command in Terminal:
df -h
and you should get back a result that looks similar to:
Filesystem      Size  Used Avail Use% Mounted on
/dev/xvda1      2.9G  1.6G  1.2G  57% /
none            4.0K     0  4.0K   0% /sys/fs/cgroup
udev            492M  8.0K  492M   1% /dev
tmpfs           100M  324K   99M   1% /run
none            5.0M     0  5.0M   0% /run/lock
none            497M     0  497M   0% /run/shm
none            100M     0  100M   0% /run/user
notice the number in line one, column &amp;quot;Avail&amp;quot;... that is the amount of disk space you have available.
Before beginning, you should update the list of available packages, this ensures that all updates
performed are against the latest levels available on the Ubuntu update servers.
To update your package list, type the following command in Terminal:
sudo apt-get update
Note: no software has been updated at this time, just the list of available packages has been updated.
  Upgrading existing packages These series of commands will update all existing packages. These will NOT install new packages.
To update all currently installed packages  to their latest levels, issue the following command in
Terminal:
sudo apt-get upgrade
The system will analyze which packages on your VM need an update and will give you an estimate
of the space needed. Make sure that the number shown here is less than the number you saw earlier
when you checked for available disk space. To be sure, add an extra 100MB to the number apt-get
is telling you. If you run out of disk space during the install, you will render your VM unusable
so proceed with extreme caution and double check that you have space available.

If you have space, answer Y to the question and let the updates start. If you don&amp;apos;t have enough
space, press ctrl-c to cancel the update and try to free up space by deleting files that you don&amp;apos;t
need before starting again.
After several screens fly by, you may end up with a screen that looks like this:

Using your arrow keys and space bar, select both options. Hit tab key to move to &amp;quot;ok&amp;quot; and then press
enter to continue.
A few screens later, you may encounter the following:

Leave the pre-selected option (&amp;quot;keep the local version currently installed&amp;quot;) as-is, hit tab to move
to &amp;quot;ok&amp;quot; and then press enter to continue.
If all went well, you will end up on a screen that looks like this and the cursor is at the command
prompt again:

Congratulations! You have just finished upgrading your existing packages to their latest official 
released levels. This will also include officially released security patches for all existing
software packages.
If you just wanted to update the  , you can stop now. If you also wish to update your Ubuntu distribution,
 then you can continue to the next section.
  Upgrading your Ubuntu Distribution This command will install new packages that have been released for Ubuntu. As before, please make
sure that you have re-checked the available disk space before proceeding.
Type in the following command to begin the update process:
sudo apt-get dist-upgrade
The command will pull in new versions of the Linux Kernel (if any are available). Just like before,
if you encounter any screens that ask for overwriting existing files, please follow the recommendations
from the previous section. Once done, you should see something like this:

Now, let&amp;apos;s reboot the VM. Open up the settings panel for your VM and toggle the on/off switch. Once 
the VM turns off and you see the button to turn it on, go ahead and click it. This is necessary
to ensure that the updated files are brought into use.
Now if you type in the following command in Terminal:
uname -rv
you should see output as the following:
3.13.0-43-generic #72-Ubuntu SMP Mon Dec 8 19:35:06 UTC 2014
note that the kernel version has updated. You&amp;apos;ve just updated your VM to the latest Linux
kernel!
  If something goes wrong Your Koding VM can easily be reinitialized to our official version (the version you got when you 
made a new Koding account) so if all these updates leave you with an unusable VM, try reinitializing
your VM back to its original state.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Koding with Sublime Text</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/koding-with-sublime-text</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-12-20T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/koding-with-sublime-text</guid>
    <author>William</author>
    <description>This guide will show you how to connect your Koding VM with Sublime Text via SFTP.
  What you will need 
Set up FTP on your Koding account: http://learn.koding.com/guides/setting-up-ftp-on-koding
Your Koding username
Your Koding VM Hostname
Sublime Text 2 or 3

  Getting Down to Business 
Download Package Control and use the Package Control: Install Package command from the command palette. The command palette is opened via ctrl+shift+p on Windows and Linux, and cmd+shift+p on OS X.


Once you run the Package Control: Install Package command, a list of packages will appear. Type in SFTP and hit enter. Using Package Control ensures Sublime SFTP will stay up to date automatically.


Open the folder that you want to sync with your VM using Sublime Text


Right click the folder in the sidebar and select SFTP/FTP -&amp;gt; Map to Remote


You should now see sftp-config.json opened.


Configure your sftp-config.json file and save it.
// sftp, ftp or ftps
 &amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;ftp&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;host&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.koding.io&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;user&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;password&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;lt;koding_password&amp;gt;&amp;quot;,
//&amp;quot;port&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;22&amp;quot;,

&amp;quot;remote_path&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/home/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/&amp;quot;,

Modify the other configurations if you wish. I personally find the option to upload_on_save very handy.


Right click the folder, select SFTP/FTP. You will now see many more options than before.


(IMPORTANT) Chose whether you want to Sync Local -&amp;gt; Remote or Sync Remote -&amp;gt; Local. Be very careful about which you choose.
Sync Local -&amp;gt; Remote overwrites what you have in your remote directory that you specified in you sftp-config.json file with what you have in your local directory.
Sync Remote -&amp;gt; Local overwrites what you have in your local directory with what you have in your remote directory that you specified in you sftp-config.json file.


(IMPORTANT) Check what is about to be performed in the box below before confirming your actions!


And there you have it, a folder synced with your Koding VM.



</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>How can I do real-time collaboration on Koding?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/collaboration</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-12-05T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/collaboration</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Note: This guide is not complete as the Collaboration feature is still experimental
  What is Collaboration? Koding Collaboration allows you to easily and effectively collaborate and share resources with your
team, students, peers or friends. When you enable Collaboration, you are effectively sharing your
virtual machine (VM) with those whom you invite into the sharing session. The session remains active
until you hit &amp;quot;End Session&amp;quot;. Every person you share a session with requires a Koding account (free or paid).
Note: Since the user(s) with whom you share your session have access to all the files on your VM, make 
sure that you are sharing with people that you know.

  What can I share? When you collaborate with someone, you can give them full access to your VM. This means that an invited
user can view/edit files and directories on your VM.
Besides file sharing, you can also share your IDE, Terminal and your Drawing board. When you start a 
sharing session, the contents of your entire workspace are shared. This includes any existing open IDE
or Terminal tabs or any new one&amp;apos;s that you open during the sharing session.
During an active Collaboration session, anything typed by any user in the sharing session is automatically
reflected on the screens of the other users in the same session. If you have ever worked on a shared
Google doc with realtime editing, this should feel very natural in comparison to that experience.
  What can I use Collaboration for? Collaboration is great for things like:

Collaborative programming
Interviews
Teaching
Bug hunting/fixing
Doing client work (with the client)

Since Koding Collaboration allows you to share your Terminal as well, it&amp;apos;s great for those times when
you are stuck with that shell script and need someone to take a peek. Koding Collaboration also
allows you to share a whiteboard for all those times when a picture is just needed.
  What does &amp;quot;Watch&amp;quot; mode mean? Watch mode, the default mode, shares your workspace and everyone in that session gets a replica of your
workspace on their screen. So if you open file tabs, new Terminals tabs and even switch tabs, other 
sessions participants see it all and their screens also update in real time with these actions.
When a session participant chooses to &amp;quot;unwatch&amp;quot; your session, it means they are free to do what they
want on their end of the collaborative session without having to be distracted by the host changing
files or opening new tabs. This is very useful when you want to work on a few different files and 
the users in the session can open files independently on the VM shared by the host yet not distract
each other. This is a bit confusing at first but then you&amp;apos;ll wonder how else would Collaboration 
ever happen!
  What does &amp;quot;Kick&amp;quot; do? This is available to the host if they want to remove someone from a shared session without ending
the session.

</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Using Github with Koding</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/using-github</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-12-04T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/using-github</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This guide will cover the basics on how to get started with Github on you Koding VM using Ungit.
  What is Ungit? Ungit is a web based interface for Github made by Fredrik Noren that runs on any platform. It has a clean and intuitive UI that makes it easy to understand git. It runs on any platform that node.js &amp;amp; git supports and it works well with GitHub. 
  Getting started Before we begin please make sure you the Koding Package Manager (KPM) installer on your VM. Follow this guide to understand wha KPM is and how to install it so you will be able to continue with this guide.
  Setup Please note that git is installed by default with every Koding VM. So you will be able to get started right away.
Before you can get started with Github on your Koding VM you need to first setup the environment to be able to work properly with Github.
Run the following command, in your Koding Terminal, to install the necessary dependency:
kpm install ungit
This will install a visually friendly interface for Github, where you will be able to interact with Github and your Koding VM. Think of it as a bridge between Koding and Github.
After the installation process has finished you will need to start the Github interface using the following command:
ungit
When the process has finished you should see a link outputted in the Terminal similar to this one:
your_koding_username.koding.io:8448
Copy that link and open it in a separate browser window. You should see something like this:

  Basic interaction In the top area of the screen, in the input box you will be able to input the path to a local existing repository on your Koding VM or start with a fresh empty one.
Please note that the input field has autocomplete
Start with a basic path like this one. Just make sure that folder exists before you input the path. If that folder doesn&amp;#x2019;t exist then you will be able to create it using this interface.
/home/your_koding_username/Web/demo
After that hit Enter || Return
You should see something like this:

Now, you can either transform that folder into a git repository or clone a repository in a subfolder in that folder.
Let&amp;#x2019;s transform this folder into a git repository. After transformation is complete just hit the little + sign at the top next to path, in order to see repository on the main view of the interface.
Before we continue, please make sure you have a Github repository ready in your Github account. Now you have to link that repository to your local Koding one using the Add new remote modal.

Copy the URL from your Github repository in this modal window and hit Submit.
Now head over to the Koding IDE and start adding code to your newly created repository. After you finished with your changes, you should already see you changes in the Ungit interface, just ready to be committed to your Github repository.
After you have named your commit, hit the commit button.
Now you can push your changes to the desired branch in your Github repository. Click on the name of the branch and then on the Push button.

You will be required to input your Github username and password before you can push your changes.

Input them, so you can continue with pushing your changes. After that you should see a successful commit of your changes.
Cloning an existing repository is a really straightforward process.
In order to clone a repository we need to have a location where we want to store our cloned repository.
Following the first step from above, in the input field at the top of Ungit select your desired path. For eg.
/home/your_koding_username/Web
Now you can clone any desired repository in this folder using this form:

Just copy the repository URL from Github, in the input field and then hit Clone repository. 
Wait for the cloning process to finish and now you should see all the commit history and you are now able to work on that repository, perform commits, push changes, using the Koding IDE.
Note: Whenever you turn on Koding VM you will have to run the ungit command to get this interface started.
If you encounter any issues or have any questions please drop an email here.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>How to change your command shell</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/change-shell</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-11-19T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/change-shell</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Koding VMs, by default, come with bash as the default command shell. There are several alternatives
to bash out there (zsh, fish, csh, tcsh, etc.) and so you may wish to change 
your command shell to something other than bash. To change your default command shell, follow these easy steps:
  Set a password for your koding VM user account Since the user account on your Koding VM&amp;apos;s does not have a default password, you need to set one first. Do the following:
sudo passwd &amp;lt;your koding username&amp;gt;

Input a password at the prompt and make sure you pick something secure. Going forward, this will be the password for the user account
on your Koding VM. Note: This does not change your Koding.com password. That remain the same.
Now type in:
chsh -s &amp;lt;path to the shell you wish to use as your default shell e.g. /bin/fish/&amp;gt;

That&amp;apos;s it. Next time you open a new Terminal, it should be running the new command shell.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting started with the Koding Package Manager</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-kpm</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-11-17T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-kpm</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Koding Package Manager (kpm) is a command line tool that we have set up to make it easy for you to install (and soon remove) your favorite packages like WordPress, Mongodb, Laravel, etc. KPM takes care of measuring disk space requirements, analyzing dependencies and installing all required packages to bring you a running system. It&amp;apos;s the easiest way to get up and running with your favorite technology or package. KPM also replaces the older generation KDApps (most of which were installers).
  Getting started with the Koding Package Manager This guide will cover the basics of the KPM and how to get started with it.
  Usage KPM runs in the Terminal of your Koding account. In order to use KPM you first need to install it. To do that you have to run the following command in your Terminal:
curl -sSL &amp;quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/koding\
/kpm-scripts/master/installers/meta&amp;quot; | fish

After the process is complete you should have access to the kpm command in your Terminal.
The basic syntax for kpm is as follows. You have access to the following commands:
kpm install &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;
kpm list
kpm -h | --help
kpm --version

The first command kpm install will install a program or a framework from the list of available programs or frameworks.
The second command kpm list will list all available installers that you can currently install on your VM. We keep adding to the list and if you wish, you can contribute as well!
The third command kpm -h or  kpm  --help will show the help for this command. The help command will showcase the syntax and a short version of this guide.
The last command kpm --version will showcase the current version of your local Koding Package Manager.

You also have available an argument for the kpm install command. 
In order to install a framework or program you need to provide the above command with an argument that represents the name of the program / framework that you want to install. For eg.
kpm install &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;
KPM is fully extensible so if you want to contribute, you can fork the project on Github and add your own installers for the Koding community!
If we are missing any packages and frameworks that you would like KPM to be able to handle, please let us know via email at support@koding.com.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting started with Jenkins</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-jenkins</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-11-12T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-jenkins</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This guide will cover the basics on how to install and configure Jenkins on your Koding VM. Just follow the steps and you should have Jenkins running in no time.
  Installing Jenkins The first thing you need to do before you install Jenkins is to make sure you add the key and source list to apt. Using the following commands you will be able to do just that.
Note: you should be logged in as root to continue with the following steps.
First add the key:
wget -q -O - http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/debian/jenkins-ci.org.key | apt-key add -
Create the sources list:
echo deb http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/debian binary/ &amp;gt; /etc/apt/sources.list.d/jenkins.list
After you finished with the above commands update apt like so:
apt-get update
You can now install Jenkins using the following command:
apt-get install jenkins
Please note that Jenkins has a lot of dependencies, so it might take some time to install them all.
  Configuring Jenkins Jenkins should now be running properly. Head over to your VMs assigned URL (If you don&amp;apos;t know what&amp;apos;s your VM URL follow this guide to find out) and append :8080 to it. That is where Jenkins currently resides.

The above image shows the default screen when you first open Jenkins.
Jenkins, by default, is insecure and everyone can access it. Head over to Manage Jenkins (in the left menu) then click Setup Security.

Follow these steps to secure your Jenkins installation:


The first thing you need to do is to enable the security setting by checking it.
Now check the box to use Jenkins&amp;apos;s own user database and disable sign ups.
Next, check the box for Matrix-based security and make sure Anonymous only has the Read right under the View group.
Click save. The page should reload and you&amp;apos;ll see a login form. You should ignore that.
Head over to your VMs URL follow by :8080. You&amp;apos;ll see a sign up form.


Sign up and this process should give administrative clearance for your Jenkins installation.
If you have any question or issues please email us at support@koding.com and we&amp;apos;ll gladly help.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Installing Apache Cordova</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-apache-cordova</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-11-04T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-apache-cordova</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This guide will cover the basics on how to get Apache Cordova installed on your Koding VM.
Before you begin please check that you have the following things installed on your Koding VM. For each requirement run each command to make sure that you have that requirement installed on your VM.
Note: By default all Koding VMs come preinstalled with the below requirements.

NodeJS

nodejs -v

NPM (Node Packaged Modules)

npm -v

Git

git --version
  Step 1 - Install In order to install Apache Cordova you will need to use NPM. Input the following command to install Apache Cordova.
sudo npm install -g cordova
  Step 2 - Finish up After the process has finished installing, the module, you need to make sure it has installed correctly. You can simply check the version using the following command:
cordova -v
The output of the above command should be something similar to this:
3.5.0-0.2.6
  Step 3 - Setting up a first project To create your first Apache Cordova app project you can use the following command:
cordova create FOLDER ID NAME
FOLDER represents the folder where the source or the project will be stored (the folder should not be created beforehand). 
ID is the reverse domain-style identifier
NAME is the application&amp;apos;s title.
If you installed NodeJS and not used the default one that came with your Koding VM you may encounter the following error:
/usr/bin/env: node: No such file or directory
In order to fix this issue you can run the following:
ln -s /usr/bin/nodejs /usr/bin/node
You now need to switch to the app folder, the one that you used above, where the source is stored, in order to add platforms:
cd FOLDER
You can add platforms like so:
cordova platform add PLATFORM_NAME
Where PLATFORM_NAME is the platform you want to add. Some of the platforms are enumerated here: ios, amazon-fireos, android, blackberry10, firefoxos, wp8, and windows8. Please do not try to add a Windows platform as this will result in an error.
If you have set everything correctly, until this point, you can go ahead an build your project using the following command (Note: Please make sure you&amp;apos;re in the project folder before inputing the below command):
cordova build
If you want to build a project for a particular platform, you can use the following command:
cordova build PLATFORM_NAME
And that&amp;apos;s it!
If you encounter any issues or have any questions regarding Apache Cordova on Koding you can email us at support@koding.com and we&amp;apos;ll gladly help.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Understanding the VM settings panel</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/understanding-vm-panel</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-11-03T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/understanding-vm-panel</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This guide will explain the basics of the VM settings panel.

In order to open the VM settings panel you need to hover over the VM name on the right side of Koding (in the sidebar at the top) and then click on the little three points icon on the right, as picture above. 

After you click on the icon mentioned above the VM modal should open, which should look like the one pictured above.
The VM settings panel has three main sections: the Basic section, the More section and the Advanced section.
  Basic section The basic section includes basic information about your VM and some basic functionality over it. Each line is explained below.

Assigned URL: This is the long assigned URL of your Koding VM.
Nickname: You can rename your VM and this will update the name that appears in the right sidebar.
On/Off toggle: The current status of the VM. You can also turn off your VM from here, though we don&amp;apos;t recommend it.
Public IP: Your VM&amp;apos;s public IP. This will change every time you start up your VM. For users on the Free plan, this will change each time you start up your VM. If your VM is Always-On, it will only change when you restart your VM.
Specs: Specifications your VM has. This is based on your current plan.
Provider: Your VM provider. In the future you will be able to choose from multiple providers.
Guides: The most common and useful guides to get you started using your VM.

  More section The more section includes some additional settings for your VM. Each setting has been explained below.

Keep VM always on toggle: If you are a paying customer than you can chose to keep your VM Always-On. This means that your VM will not be shut down automatically after 60 minutes.
Domains: You can enable a short URL for your VM and/or define subdomains and custom domains for your VM.

  Advanced section The advanced section includes settings that only advanced users should use. If you are an unexperienced user then this section should be off limits.

Reinitialize VM: This button will set your VM back to its default state. This means that the VM will be re-imaged, as if you deleted the VM and created a new one. This guide explains the reinit function in more detail.
Terminate VM: If you&amp;apos;re a paying customer you can remove your VM and create a new one if you so choose.

If you encounter any issues or have any questions regarding the VM settings panel you can email us at support@koding.com and we&amp;apos;ll gladly help.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Koding Subdomains and VHosts</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/vhosts-and-subdomains</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-11-03T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/vhosts-and-subdomains</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll go over setting up a Koding subdomain to point to a 
directory of your choice.
  Creating Subdomains To create a subdomain, refer to the Subdomain Section 
here
  Creating a Virtual Host First, run the following command, where mysubdomain is the name of your subdomain.
sudo touch /etc/apache2/sites-available/mysubdomain.conf

Next, open the above file with nano, vim, or whatever command line 
editor you prefer. We&amp;apos;re using a command line editor, because files 
located in /etc/apache2/sites-available are owned by root, and 
require sudo.
If you used nano, your command should look like this:
sudo nano /etc/apache2/sites-available/mysubdomain.conf

Now that you have the file open with your preferred editor, paste in the 
following code:
&amp;lt;Virtualhost *:80&amp;gt;
  ServerName mysubdomain.username.koding.io
  DocumentRoot /var/www/myDirectory
&amp;lt;/Virtualhost&amp;gt;

There are a two things you&amp;apos;re going to have to change here, so lets go over them.

ServerName: The value of ServerName should be your full subdomain 
url, without the http.

DocumentRoot: This is the folder location that you want the 
subdomain to direct to. Remember that /var/www equals ~/Web, so in 
the given example, /var/www/myDirectory equals ~/Web/myDirectory.  


&amp;lt;Virtualhost *:80&amp;gt;
  ServerName hello.joshmurray.koding.io
  DocumentRoot /var/www/helloworld
&amp;lt;/Virtualhost&amp;gt;

Note: The DocumentRoot has to be an absolute path. Relative 
directories such as /var/www/../foo and ~/MyDirectory will not work.If you would like to supply an directory outside of ~/Web, use your 
full home path, eg: /home/joshmurray/myNotWebDirectory
  Enable the Subdomain Lastly, we need to add our &amp;quot;site&amp;quot; and reload apache. Run the following 
two commands, replacing mysubdomain with the name of your subdomain.
sudo a2ensite mysubdomain
sudo service apache2 reload

  Confirming To confirm you did all the steps completely, connect to 
http://mysubdomain.username.koding.io and you should see whatever you 
have in your directory of choice. 
  Troubleshooting   Apache 404 If you see a plain white page saying &amp;quot;Not Found&amp;quot; with mentions of 
Apache and Ubuntu, then Apache is correctly loading a directory, but the 
directory is empty. Confirm that your DocumentRoot is a correct, and an 
absolute directory.
  Forbidden By default, Apache is configured to not allow access to directories 
outside of /var/www. So, if you link to an absolute directory outside 
of /var/www, such as /home/joshmurray/hello, you may see a message 
similar to the following.
You do not have permission to access / on this server.
To resolve this, you can use the &amp;lt;Directory&amp;gt; directive inside of your 
VirtualHost directive from above. Example:
&amp;lt;Virtualhost *:80&amp;gt;
  ServerName hello.joshmurray.koding.io
  DocumentRoot /home/joshmurray/hello
  &amp;lt;Directory /home/joshmurray/hello/&amp;gt;
    Options Indexes FollowSymLinks
    AllowOverride None
    Require all granted
  &amp;lt;/Directory&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/Virtualhost&amp;gt;

Afterwards, don&amp;apos;t forget to reload Apache, with the following command.
sudo service apache2 reload

Important: It is recommended that you review the Directory directive 
documentation, 
as there are security implications to allowing directory access, that you 
should understand.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Changing your IDE and Terminal themes</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/change-theme</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-28T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/change-theme</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Changing your IDE and Terminal theme is very easy. Not everyone likes the default colors
and fonts so we&amp;apos;ve put together a slew of choices for you to pick from.
To get started, simply head over to your IDE settings panel (as shown in the image below)
and select the IDE and Terminal theme that suits you best. As you select a new theme, the
theme color scheme and font should reflect in the editor and Terminal in real time.
Enjoy your new theme!

</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Installing PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-postgresql</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-22T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-postgresql</guid>
    <author>Koding Team</author>
    <description>PostgreSQL is an open source relational database management system that 
provides an implementation of the SQL query language. In this guide, 
we&amp;apos;ll go over installing PostgreSQL on your Koding VM. Lets get started!
  Updating, and Installing We can install Postgres by using apt-get. To do this, open your 
Terminal and paste in the following two commands.
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install postgresql postgresql-contrib
Once these two commands finish Postgres should be installed and running.
  Confirming Your Installing To confirm your Installation and that Postgres is running, run the 
following command in your Terminal.
service postgresql status
It should respond with approximately the following.
9.3/main (port 5432): online
  Connecting and Using PostgreSQL For instructions on using Postgres, see the Using PostgreSQL 
guide.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Koding Chat Introduction</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/chat-introduction</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-19T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/chat-introduction</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description></description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>A guide to Docker</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/what-is-docker</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-17T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/what-is-docker</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Docker is a platform that helps developers build apps in whatever language they feel comfortable using and using any toolchain they want. Using Docker developers can build, ship and run distributed applications because it enables them to quickly put together an app by eliminating the stress between development, QA and production environments.
A developer that uses Docker can run his / hers app anywhere without the fear of it not performing as it should.
Apps that are built using Docker are completely portable and can run anywhere.
  Docker apps Anyone can get started with Docker by checking out one of the 13,000+ apps that are available in the Docker Hub. You can get started working on WordPress or a new nodejs project in just a few seconds without the hassle of having to install any other dependencies (other then Docker of course) on your Koding VM.
  Benefits The difference between a virtualized application and the Docker Engine container is that the first one includes not only the app and the necessary binaries and libraries but it contains the guest OS as well. The later runs as an separate process on the OS and thus it has the resources separation and allocation of a VM but is much more portable.
  Installing Docker on Koding The version of Ubuntu that is installed on each Koding VM comes with a docker.io package and it should install Docker 0.9.1. 
We can install Docker on our Koding VM using the following commands:

We update the package list

sudo apt-get update

Install Docker

sudo apt-get install docker.io

We create a link 

sudo ln -sf /usr/bin/docker.io /usr/local/bin/docker

We need to edit the docker file in order to continue

sudo sed -i &amp;apos;$acomplete -F _docker docker&amp;apos; /etc/bash_completion.d/docker.io

And we now execute that file

source /etc/bash_completion.d/docker.io

After that we need to add the Docker repo key to the local keychain

sudo apt-key adv --keyserver hkp://keyserver.ubuntu.com:80 --recv-keys 36A1D7869245C8950F966E92D8576A8BA88D21E9

The last step is to add the Docker repo to the apt sources list, update and install the lxc-docker package. You can do that using the following commands

sudo sh -c &amp;quot;echo deb https://get.docker.com/ubuntu docker main\
&amp;gt; /etc/apt/sources.list.d/docker.list&amp;quot;
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install lxc-docker
Note: You can use the below command, that uses curl, for an easier installation process:
curl -sSL https://get.docker.com/ubuntu/ | sudo sh
If you made it to this point you can run this command to check if Docker is indeed installed and works properly:
sudo docker run -i -t ubuntu /bin/bash
If you have any question or issues please email us at support@koding.com and we&amp;apos;ll gladly help.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started: File Uploads</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/file-upload</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-17T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/file-upload</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll take a look at uploading your files and projects to 
Koding, in multiple ways. Lets get started!
  Uploading with Drag and Drop The simplest way, is simply by using Drag and Drop file upload! To do 
this, open your Koding IDE, locate your FileTree on the left hand
side, and drag a file from your Desktop onto the FileTree. An example 
image is below.

After you let go of the file, your file will be uploaded to your 
~/Uploads directory.
  Uploading with FTP FTP is another common way to upload files to your VM. Before uploading 
with FTP though, you&amp;apos;ll need to set up an FTP Server on your VM.
The FTP Guide will take you through both the installation, and 
connecting process, so check it out!
  Uploading with SCP SCP is is a tool that will copy files from your local Unix filesystem 
to a remote filesystem over SSH connections. To use it, make sure you 
have SSH setup with your Koding VM beforehand. Instructions can be found 
here if needed.
After that, use the following command to copy a local file to your VM.
scp LOCAL_FILE USERNAME.koding.io:REMOTE_FILE
Replace LOCAL_FILE with your local file location, USERNAME with your 
Koding Username, and REMOTE_FILE with your Remote File location. An 
example of this command can be seen below.
scp ~/my_image.png joshmurray.koding.io:~/my_image.png
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Installing MongoDB</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/install-mongodb</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-17T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/install-mongodb</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Before you continue reading this guide why not try a more easy way, using the Koding Package Manager (kpm) and install MongoDB using just one command:
kpm install mongodb

In this short guide we&amp;apos;ll explain how to install MongoDB, and modify
it&amp;apos;s configuration to run in a small storage environment. Lets get 
started!
  Installation Installation is easy, and can be done with apt-get, as seen in the 
following command.
sudo apt-get install mongodb
That&amp;apos;s it! You can start Mongo with the following command:
sudo service mongodb start
NOTE: If you&amp;apos;re running Mongo on a Free Koding VM, read below..
  Configuring for Limited Storage If you&amp;apos;re running Mongo on a Free VM, you&amp;apos;ll need to configure it to use 
small files. To do that, open up the /etc/mongodb.conf file with the
following command:
sudo nano /etc/mongodb.conf
With that file open, navigate to the bottom and add the following line:
smallfiles=true
Now use ctrl-x to save the file. After you&amp;apos;ve saved the file, simply 
restart Mongodb with the following command:
sudo service mongodb restart
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Install WordPress</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-wordpress</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-16T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-wordpress</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Before you continue reading this guide why not try a more easy way, using the Koding Package Manager (kpm) and install WordPress using just one command:
kpm install wordpress

This guide will walk you through the steps required to install WordPress on your Koding VM. We will walk through the steps needed to download, install, configure and eventually run a full WordPress system.
  WordPress requirements Before we begin you may want to make sure you have the following things installed on your Koding VM.

PHP 5.2.4 or greater
MySQL 5.0 or greater
The mod_rewrite Apache module

After you made sure and/or installed the above requirements you can go ahead a continue with the guide.
  Step 1 - Database creation The first thing we need for our WordPress installation to work is a new database. We can create one using either:

the command line
via phpMyAdmin.

The rest of this guide will focus on the command line method to create a database for our WordPress installation.
  Setting up MySQL: Type in the commands listed below in a Koding Terminal.

Login to mySQL as the root user:

mysql -u root -p

Create a new database:

CREATE DATABASE wordpress;

Create a new user and assign a password:

CREATE USER dbuser@localhost IDENTIFIED BY &amp;apos;your_password&amp;apos;;

Give that user permission to access that database using the following command:

GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON wordpress.* TO dbuser@localhost;

Apply the changes so that mySQL knows about them:

FLUSH PRIVILEGES;

exit
  Step 2 - Configuring WordPress The first thing we need to do is to head over to our Web folder like so type in the following command in Terminal:
cd ~/Web
Now, we need to download the latest WordPress release. We can do that using the following command:
wget http://wordpress.org/latest.zip
Unzip the downloaded file:
unzip latest.zip
All of the wordpress install files will now be extracted into a older named wordpress (that you can rename afterwards if you want to).
The last thing we need to do before we can start the installation process is to set up the link between WordPress and the database we created earlier. We can achieve this by typing in the following commands in Terminal:

Head over to the wordpress folder:

cd wordpress

Rename the default config file:

cp wp-config-sample.php wp-config.php

Edit the config file via the command line:

nano wp-config.php

Add the proper database info into the config file and then save it:

// ** MySQL settings - You can get this info from your web host ** //
/** The name of the database for WordPress */
define(&amp;apos;DB_NAME&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;database_name&amp;apos;);

/** MySQL database username */
define(&amp;apos;DB_USER&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;username&amp;apos;);

/** MySQL database password */
define(&amp;apos;DB_PASSWORD&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;password&amp;apos;);

/** Stop WordPress from asking for FTP credentials */
define(&amp;apos;FS_METHOD&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;direct&amp;apos;);
The above variables: database_name, username, password should be replaced with the values you set when creating the database on Step 1.
The last thing that we need to do before we begin the install, is to set up the uploads folder. That can be achieved like so:

From the command line we create a folder:

mkdir wp-content/uploads

We need to give the web server write permission to all WordPress files so you can make changes to the install directly from within WordPress. You can achieve this by using the following commands:

sudo chown -R www-data:www-data wp-content/uploads

sudo chmod -R 755 wp-content/uploads
  Step 3 - Finalizing the WordPress install Open up a new browser tab and navigate to your VM&amp;apos;s hostname and add /wordpress at the end. If you don&amp;apos;t know what you VM hostname is, follow this guide to find out.
You should see the initial configuration page. It should look like this:

Now you just need to follow the instructions on screen and finish the install!
If you encounter any issues or have any questions regarding WordPress on Koding you can email us at support@koding.com and we&amp;apos;ll gladly help.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Install phpMyAdmin</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/install-phpmyadmin</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-11T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/install-phpmyadmin</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Before you continue reading this guide why not try a more easy way, using the Koding Package Manager (kpm) and install phpMyAdmin using just one command:
kpm install phpmyadmin

This guide will walk you through the steps you need to take in order to get phpMyAdmin installed on your Koding VM.
Just follow the steps and you should get phpMyAdmin installed in no time.
  Step 1 The first thing that we need to do is to update our package list. We can do that using the following command.
sudo apt-get update
After that we can go ahead and install phpmyadmin using the following command:
sudo apt-get install phpmyadmin
  Step 2 During the installation process you will be prompted to answer some questions in order to configure the installation properly.
When asked to choose the server, you need to select apache2.

For the next question select Ok.

You need to select Yes for the next step in order to set up the database using dbconfig-common.

Choose a password for your root user.

And then a password for the phpmyadmin installation.

Last step is to confirm that password.
  Step 3 After the installation process has finished we have to make sure that the Apache server is serving phpmyadmin properly. In order to do that we need to edit the Apache configuration file. You can use the following command.
sudo nano /etc/apache2/apache2.conf
And at the very bottom of the file we need to include the following line.
Include /etc/phpmyadmin/apache.conf
Save the file.
One more thing that we need to do before we can see everything working is to enable the mcrypt extension. We can do that using the following command.
sudo php5enmod mcrypt
  Step 4 Restart the Apache server using the following command and you should see everything working.
sudo service apache2 restart
You will now be able to access phpmyadmin by following a similar URL:
http://KODING_USERNAME.koding.io/phpmyadmin
Find out more about your VM hostname here.
And that&amp;apos;s it.
If you encounter any issues or have any questions please drop an email here.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Koding IDE Introduction</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/ide-introduction</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-10T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/ide-introduction</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description></description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Koding Terminal Introduction</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/terminal-introduction</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-10T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/terminal-introduction</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description></description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Koding Virtual Machines Introduction</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/vm-introduction</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-10T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/vm-introduction</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description></description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting started with Drupal 8 (Prerelease)</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-drupal8-beta</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-02T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-drupal8-beta</guid>
    <author>Nik LePage</author>
    <description>A quick rundown of how to setup a development environment for checking out the new Drupal 8 releases.
  Setting up the development environment Go ahead and open up the Koding dev UI. The terminal is available in the bottom right panel. (I&amp;apos;m assuming you&amp;#x2019;re in ~/Web for the actual site install bits).
We must first install Composer as we need Drush master (7) to easily install Drupal 8. You wanted Drush anyway though, right? :)
Issue the following commands to perform the install and tidy up. 
sudo curl -sS https://getcomposer.org/installer | php
sudo mv composer.phar /usr/local/bin/composer

The last step is not required AFAIK, but makes Composer global for the machine. The instructions that I read said &amp;#x201C;Make sure Composer&amp;apos;s global bin directory is on the system PATH (recommended)&amp;#x201D;. That&amp;#x2019;s great, although I don&amp;#x2019;t fully understand the implications. 

Issue the following commands in your shell to sort the path out.
sed -i &amp;apos;1i export PATH=&amp;quot;$HOME/.composer/vendor/bin:$PATH&amp;quot;&amp;apos; $HOME/.bashrc
source $HOME/.bashrc
Now we can go ahead and use Composer to install drush 7. More long winded than &amp;quot;the old days&amp;quot;, but get used to it. Everything is Composer in D8. &amp;quot;So Compose; much baton (sic).&amp;quot;
composer global require drush/drush:dev-master
Test the install with a random &amp;#x201C;drush&amp;#x201D; command in the shell... e.g.
drush --version
As it turns out, we also need to enable mod_rewrite, although this appears to be set up by default in the new Koding. In order to do so, you can type the following command.
sudo a2enmod rewrite
MySQL is not installed by default in the new Koding setup. We need to add MariaDB, and the necessary PHP extensions.
# Follow the instructions at https://downloads.mariadb.org/mariadb/repositories/#mirror=coreix
# Select &amp;quot;Ubuntu&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;14.04&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;5.5&amp;quot; and then a mirror, and the instructions are below
sudo apt-get install php5-mysql php5-gd
One more gotcha - D8 requires (or prefers) curl?! Well, okay.
sudo apt-get install php5-curl
Restart the web server to enable all the new goodness!
sudo service apache2 restart
  Setting up the Drupal environment Now we&amp;#x2019;re ready to rock! The rest of this is a pretty standard Drupal setup mission, but here&amp;apos;s the outline anyway. Go setup yourself up a new database by entering MySql CLI (Koding mysql automatically assumes root) and issue the following commands.
mysql -u root -p  # to get into the CLI, then...

CREATE DATABASE drupal8db;
GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON drupal8db.* TO myusername@localhost IDENTIFIED BY &amp;apos;mypassword&amp;apos;;
FLUSH privileges;
You probably (almost certainly) don&amp;#x2019;t want to use your root password again in case you&amp;#x2019;re going to be using the included shared environments that Koding provides.
Now cd ~/Web and install Drupal 8. 
Choose a version: drush dl drupal-8 (this may give you a choice of versions)
OR Definitely :) get Drupal 8 Beta 1: wget http://ftp.drupal.org/files/projects/drupal-8.0.0-beta1.tar.gz (see: https://www.drupal.org/node/2348025 )
Unpack the tarball with tar zxf drupal-8-whatever.tgz
Alter the dir name if it bothers you or you need a reminder of which version you&amp;#x2019;re using.
mv drupal-8-whatever mydrupaldir
I&amp;apos;m assuming a subdirectory from here on - which means you should set the RewriteBase in .htaccess
RewriteBase /mydrupaldir  # in .htaccess in ~/Web/mydrupaldir
Save yourself a few seconds by doing the usual copying of settings.php and set permissions malarky. 
cd mydrupaldir
cd sites/default
# for developers only (sets up some dev mode settings, do this before install!)
cp ../example.settings.local.php ./settings.local.php
# for everyone
cp default.settings.php settings.php
cp default.services.yml services.yml
chmod 0666 settings.php services.yml
mkdir files
sudo chown myuser:www-data files # NB this is server/user specific!
chmod 0775 files
(You need to change these permissions back to something more sane afterwards&amp;#x2026; 0644 and 0775 seem to be ok, but I&amp;#x2019;m open to abuse on the matter.)
And you&amp;#x2019;re off! To open your VM in a browser, click the ellipsis next to your VM name (probably koding-vm-0) and then the VM name to open the site in a new tab, and follow the usual Drupal installer instructions! NB If you&amp;apos;re a developer, you might want to check out Webchick&amp;apos;s setup video from Drupalcon AMS: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wKdU2Q1NIZQ
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started with C and C++</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-c-cpp</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-02T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-c-cpp</guid>
    <author>drodri</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll introducing C and C++ and how to build your first programs 
in Koding. 
C and C++ are the reference languages in many domains, from heavy computations,
research, robotics, embedded systems, financing and banking...
They are compiled languages, you write source code and a compiler translate it to
native binaries, that typically can run only in the platform they were compiled to
(Win, Linux, Mac). The process of converting source code to executable binaries,
that involve compiling and linking is called the build process. This process can
be specified by different means, e.g. using an IDE or Makefiles. 
  Running your first C program Lets create our first &amp;quot;Hello world&amp;quot; C application, and build it.
Open up your Ace editor, and open up a new file by pressing the Plus Button on the 
tab list. If your file says Untitled.txt, you&amp;apos;re good to go.
Next, paste the following code into the file.
#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;

void main(){
    printf(&amp;quot;Hello world\n&amp;quot;);
}
We haven&amp;apos;t saved our file yet , so use Ctrl-S to save the file, 
and name it main.c (note the extension c, not cpp).
Finally, open up the Koding Terminal 
and build and run your application.
$ gcc -o hello main.c                                                                            
$ ./hello
Hello world
  Running your first C++ program Create another file, this time named &amp;quot;main.cpp&amp;quot; with the following code:
#include &amp;lt;iostream&amp;gt;

using namespace std;

int main(){
    cout &amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot; &amp;lt;&amp;lt; endl;
    return 0;
}
Now we will build it with the g++ compiler, and run it. Please note that
even if they are similar, C++ is not an &amp;quot;extension&amp;quot; of C or C with classes but
a very different language by itself.
$ g++ -o hellopp main.cpp
$ ./hellopp
Hello world
Building larger applications can be somewhat difficult and cumbersome to the newbie.
As soon as your application start to have several files, you will need to define
how to build them in Makefiles, but we would rather recommend using the CMake build system,
which is much simpler and fully portable to Windows and Mac platforms, with support
for many compilers, as Visual Studio, and IDEs as Eclipse.
The Biicode platform automatically generate CMake files for you, based on 
your source code files. It also manage dependencies, so it can be used for reusing
existing code easily.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>What happens upon upgrade?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/what-happens-upon-upgrade</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-02T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/what-happens-upon-upgrade</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>You just upgraded your account, awesome (and thanks!) but what happens now?
Based on the type of plan you selected on the Pricing page you now have access to more resources as compared to your free Koding account. These resources fall into the following categories:

Ability to mark your VM(s) as Always-On
Add more storage to your VM(s)

  Utilizing new resources when upgrading to the Hobbyist Plan Once you have upgraded to Hobbyist, you can mark your VM as an Always-On VM and increase its storage from 3GB to 10GB. To to this, head over to the settings panel for your VM and follow these easy steps:

head over to VM settings (as shown in the image below)
expand the &amp;quot;More&amp;quot; panel and then the &amp;quot;Advanced&amp;quot; panel
You will see a new button under the Advanced panel labeled &amp;quot;Resize&amp;quot; (this button only appears for users who have upgraded to the Hobbyist plan and have not yet allocated the 10GB. Once you allocate it, the button will disappear)
Click the button to initiate resize. Once done, your VM will show 10GB. Verify that using the command df -h /


  Utilizing new resources when upgrading to the Developer and Professional Plans Under these plans, you can have a total of up to 3 (for Developer) and 5 (for Professional) VMs, mark any of them as Always-On and allocate 25GB (for Developer) / 50GB (for Professional) of storage amonst them. You will start with the default free VM and it is up to you whether you want to leave it at the default 3GB or delete it so that you can make a new one with a storage allocation that you prefer. To delete a VM, simply go the settings panel of the VM and click the Terminate button (as shown in the attached screen shot).

To create a new VM, click the + icon in the VM list and you will be presented wit the option to create a new VM with a space allocation that is preferable to you (as shown below).

Enjoy the new resources and thanks again for upgrading! If you have any addtional questions regarding upgrades and resources, please send us a support request and we will get back to you as soon as possible.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Building C / C++ applications with biicode</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-biicode</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-10-02T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-biicode</guid>
    <author>drodri</author>
    <description>Building larger applications can be somewhat difficult and cumbersome to the newbie.
As soon as your application start to have several files, you will need to define
how to build them in Makefiles or using the CMake build system.
We will be using in the following examples biicode, which is a dependency manager
that allows to easily retrieve existing code and also manages to automatically generate
build files for your project.
You can install it running from your terminal:
$ wget http://apt.biicode.com/install.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; chmod +x install.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ./install.sh
After it finish, you can run a helper command that install an updated version of CMake:
$ bii setup:cpp
Lets build an application that computes the SHA1 of a string. Usually you dont want to write
yourself such algorithm, but rather use an existing implementation.
The following commands will create a project and a &amp;quot;Hello world&amp;quot; file, which you can build and
run:
$ bii init cryptoproject
$ cd cryptoproject
$ bii new myuser/crypto --hello=cpp
$ bii cpp:build
$ ./bin/myuser_crypto_main
Hello world!
Now replace the contents of the &amp;quot;main.cpp&amp;quot; file inside the blocks/myuser/crypto folder with:
#include &amp;quot;cryptopp/cryptopp/sha.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;cryptopp/cryptopp/filters.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;cryptopp/cryptopp/hex.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;lt;iostream&amp;gt;
#include &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;

int main() {
    CryptoPP::SHA1 sha1;
    std::string source = &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot;;  
    std::string hash = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
    CryptoPP::StringSource(source, true, new CryptoPP::HashFilter(sha1,
                            new CryptoPP::HexEncoder(new CryptoPP::StringSink(hash))));
    std::cout &amp;lt;&amp;lt; hash &amp;lt;&amp;lt; std::endl;
}
If you now try to build this example, it will fail. You can try to do so, and then check
your dependencies:
$ bii cpp:build
$ bii deps
The code depends on some external code, the Crypto++ library. This can be easily retrieved
with the &amp;quot;find&amp;quot; command
$ bii find
Now you can build and run it:
$ bii cpp:build
$ ./bin/myuser_crypto_main
F7FF9E8B7BB2E09B70935A5D785E0CC5D9D0ABF0
For further examples, you can have a look to the biicode C/C++ documentation and the 
examples
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started: Workspaces</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/workspaces</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-09-18T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/workspaces</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll go over what Koding Workspaces are, and how 
to manage them. Lets get started!
  What are they? Workspaces are a way to save the arrangement of your IDE. Open Files, 
Terminals, and File Explorer, Workspaces help you save not just what 
you&amp;apos;re working on but how you&amp;apos;re working.
Furthermore, in upcoming releases workspaces will have integration with 
various services and developer tools, making them a quick way to get 
started with a specific type of Project or Service.
  How to use them? 
Workspaces, highlighted in the above image, can be opened simply by 
clicking on them. Creating new workspaces is as simple as using the Plus 
button, in the upper right of the highlighted area.
Or you can simply right click on a folder from the FileTree and create a Workspace from there. Like in the image below.

With the workspace open, simply use the IDE as you want. Open 
files, Terminals, Browsers, and Drawing Boards will be remembered between 
programming sessions.
  Workspaces on the File System With each user created Workspace, a directory is created inside the 
~/Workspaces directory.
You can open this directory in your Terminal or clone your projects 
directly into it as you like.
  Linking Workspaces to Existing Directories Workspace folders are just normal folders on the file system. As such, we 
can use Unix symbolic links to folders to achieve what we want. As an 
example, lets create a Workspace linked to our Web directory.
Open up a Terminal, and type in the following commands.
mkdir -p ~/Workspaces
ln -s ~/Web ~/Workspaces/Web
Now, with the Koding UI, create a new workspace named Web. That&amp;apos;s it!Now when you click on the workspace, the FileTree will automatically open 
to the Web folder&amp;apos;s contents.
It should be noted that we created our link before we created the 
Workspace. If the workspace already existed, the link would not be set 
correctly.
You can freely remove the Workspace file system and replace them with any 
links you desire, as the steps above use, but just be careful not to 
delete any of your files in the process.
Note: the default Workspace can&amp;apos;t be removed as that is the default Web folder on your VM.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Connect with SSH, from Unix</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/ssh-into-your-vm</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-09-15T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/ssh-into-your-vm</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Connecting to your VM with SSH will allow you to use another Terminal, 
outside of Koding, to interact with your Koding VM. If you&amp;apos;re using 
Cygwin, these instructions will work fine for you.
We are going to use the terminology &amp;quot;local&amp;quot; to represent the machine that 
you&amp;apos;re connecting to Koding with.
  What you will need 
Your Koding username
Your Koding VM Address
An SSH Key on your local machine. If you don&amp;apos;t have a key, Github has 
an awesome tutorial found here.

  Copy your Public Key First, copy your Public Key, usually found in ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub, and 
copy it in its entirety. Note the .pub in the filename. This is the 
public key, and it is very important that you copy this one. It will 
look something like this.
ssh-rsa AAAAB3NzaC1yc2EAAAADAQABAAABAQCyhKankDE4DRM86JqZ3JPdWDeqg+Tbzlql
TLfOKTeokhRoMgy5WoMY/ZWUVES3d2vSHHwW3cwWlELmVdc3Ow57boZv3fOsPhybYHVRTClX
Yr1ncSxyTvjvCfvV5q22aIxHPWQ353543ssda87sa+85XEa4VnveJsEzxBZl4oJ4GB0AGa48
+UdIqutrgZu7D7JCK+Yl228X+3bJf3ddlqDaKaVXPivvvYqImK6ZwFsxh2lNO4E8IOd3OSK9
zv6i+io8PxWmwP0tLFokxulAI8Td1sOPBE9s9bdJ5c2T/GfGjKF+aNKsd33TsYEjjc/plMZm
RRrOgQwre6OAkgMvyV2X foo@bar.baz
  Adding to your Authorized Keys Next, we need to create a file called authorized_keys on your Koding 
VM, and paste the previously copied key into it. Run the following 
commands in your Koding Terminal.
mkdir -p ~/.ssh
touch ~/.ssh/authorized_keys
Now, open up the authorized_keys file that you just created, and paste 
in your public key. To open the file you can use a Terminal editor such 
as Nano or Vim, or simply use the File Explorer on the left hand side to 
open the ~/.ssh/authorized_keys file.
Once the key has been pasted in, save the file.
  Connecting with SSH Lastly, open up your local Terminal client and ssh to your VM Address as 
shown below. If you do not know your VM Address, instructions to find it 
can be found here.
ssh username@vmaddress
Replace username with your username, and vmaddress with your VM 
Address. As an example, here is a filled our ssh command.
ssh joshmurray@unkk05c3f84e.joshmurray.koding.io
  Troubleshooting If you experience trouble, try connecting to your VM with the -vv flag 
and share the output with Koding users. An example of the above ssh 
command with the -vv flag is below.
ssh -vv joshmurray@unkk05c3f84e.joshmurray.koding.io
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Setting up FTP on Koding</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/setting-up-ftp-on-koding</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-09-15T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/setting-up-ftp-on-koding</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Before you continue reading this guide why not try a more easy way, using the Koding Package Manager (kpm) and install FTP using just one command:
kpm install ftp

In this guide we&amp;apos;ll go over how to get your FTP Client connected to your 
VM&amp;apos;s FTP Server. We will be using FileZilla as the FTP 
Client, but any client should be able to connect to your FTP Server 
successfully.
  What you will need In this tutorial you will need the following.

A Koding account, and your Koding Username.
The Address of the VM you&amp;apos;d like to connect to. Instructions can be 
found here.

  Installing ProFTPd First off, we&amp;apos;ll need to install ProFTPd. This can be done by pasting 
the following command into your Koding IDE&amp;apos;s Terminal.
sudo apt-get install proftpd
During the install process you will be asked to choose to run your VPS as an inetd or standalone server. Choose the standalone option.
  Setting up the FTP User After ProFTPd has been successfully installed, we need to set a FTP password for your user. To do 
this, paste the following command into your Terminal.
sudo passwd KODING_USERNAME
Make note to replace KODING_USERNAME with your actual Koding username.
After hitting enter, you&amp;apos;ll be prompted for the FTP password you wish 
to use. Not your Koding password.
  Connecting to your FTP Server Finally, in your FTP Client of choice paste your VM Address into the 
hostname. If you&amp;apos;re not sure what that is, instructions to find it can be 
found here.
After the Hostname, enter your Koding username, and FTP Password that you 
chose in the above commands. An example image from FileZilla can be seen 
below.

  Additional Resources 
FileZilla
FileZilla Download

</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Custom Domains with your Koding VM</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/domains</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-09-02T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/domains</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>


Koding VMs support custom domains as long as your domain provider 
supports one of the following record types.

CNAME Record
A Record

  Find your VM Address First, you&amp;apos;ll need to find and copy your VM Address. To 
find this, please refer to this guide - But it will look 
something like the address below:
ulkk3a3a4bb3.joshmurray.koding.io
  Create Your Domain Record Next, you&amp;apos;ll need to create and configure either a CNAME Record, or 
an A Record with your domain provider.
To configure either of these record types, refer to your providers guides 
and create the record type which you prefer.
Once you have created it, paste in the VM Address from above to the 
Record Value. This will point your Domain to the Address that the host 
resolves to.
  The Waiting Game If the record you are creating is new, it should resolve very quickly. If 
however, it is an older record you must wait for the cache to expire. 
This may take anywhere from 5 minutes to 24 hours.
If it has not been resolved after a day, ensure that you used the proper 
VM Address (as shown above). If it is correct, try contacting your 
Domain Provider and ensure that they are able to use Addresses rather 
than IPs in their record values.
  Can I use my VMs IP? For technical reasons, free VMs have rotating IPs. After your VM goes 
offline, it is not guaranteed to boot up with the same IP. This means 
that you should not use your VMs IP as the record value if you&amp;apos;re 
not using an Always-On VM.
If however your VM is Always-On, an IP should work, as long as your VM is 
not shutdown. For more information on Always-On VMs, see the Pricing 
Page.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started with Ruby</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-ruby</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-20T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-ruby</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll explain what Ruby is, and how to write a simple web 
server using the built in Socket library. So, lets get started!
  What is Ruby Ruby is a popular, general purpose, high level programing language. It 
focuses on readability programmer enjoyment over raw performance. Koding 
VMs come pre-installed with Ruby and RubyGem, making it super easy to get 
started. Lets see what it looks like to run some Ruby code!
  Running your first Ruby script Open up your Ace Editor and create a new file named hello.rb.Paste in the following code into that file.
puts &amp;quot;Hello from Ruby!&amp;quot;

The puts name is a function which takes a string and prints it to the 
Standard Output (STDOUT) of the process. Lets try running this file and 
see the output, but first save the file with Ctrl-s. Now, open up 
your Terminal and type in the following command.
ruby hello.rb
You should see output similar to this:
joshmurray: ~ $ ruby hello.rb
Hello from Ruby!
joshmurray: ~ $
Neat! Now that we know how to run some code, lets look at a real example 
of some Ruby code.
  Your first Ruby web server Just like before, create a new file named web.rb, and paste in the 
following code.
require &amp;apos;socket&amp;apos;

server = TCPServer.new &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;, 3000

loop do
  socket  = server.accept
  request = socket.gets
  puts request

  response = &amp;quot;Hello World!\n&amp;quot;
  socket.print &amp;quot;HTTP/1.1 200 OK\r\n&amp;quot; +
               &amp;quot;Content-Type: text/plain\r\n&amp;quot; +
               &amp;quot;Content-Length: #{response.bytesize}\r\n&amp;quot; +
               &amp;quot;Connection: close\r\n&amp;quot;
  socket.print &amp;quot;\r\n&amp;quot;

  socket.print response
  socket.close
end

That looks a bit complicated, so lets break it down piece by piece.
require &amp;apos;socket&amp;apos;
server = TCPServer.new &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;, 3000

First, we use require to import the socket module. TCPServer comes 
from this module, and we use it to create a new Socket server on 
0.0.0.0:3000. This is a plain socket server, meaning that we&amp;apos;re 
going to implement an HTTP response ourselves. Getting our hands dirty!
loop do
  socket  = server.accept
  puts socket.gets

Next up, loop do creates a never ending loop. Each iteration of the 
loop executes until server.accept. This blocks, waiting for connections 
from our TCP Server.
When your browser connects to the TCP Server, the socket servers returns 
a connection object named socket. From that object, we use gets to 
read a line from the incoming data Stream.
The incoming stream is what your browser sent to the TCP Server as part 
of it&amp;apos;s request. So with socket.gets you&amp;apos;re simply reading what your 
browser sent. We then take that, and use puts to print it to the STDOUT 
just like in our Hello example above. Note that we&amp;apos;re just printing to 
STDOUT to help us understand when requests are incoming, it is not 
required.
  response = &amp;quot;Hello World!\n&amp;quot;
  socket.print &amp;quot;HTTP/1.1 200 OK\r\n&amp;quot; +
               &amp;quot;Content-Type: text/plain\r\n&amp;quot; +
               &amp;quot;Content-Length: #{response.bytesize}\r\n&amp;quot; +
               &amp;quot;Connection: close\r\n&amp;quot;
  socket.print &amp;quot;\r\n&amp;quot;

Next up, we start building our response. We start by writing &amp;quot;Hello 
World!\n&amp;quot; to the variable response. We then print a series of strings 
to the socket.
This section can get a little confusing, because it involves returning 
HTTP Headers to the requesting browser. We won&amp;apos;t go into detail of this 
here, but just understand that this is part of the HTTP Spec, that we&amp;apos;re 
manually implementing.
As part of these headers, we print the Content-Length, which is the 
number of bytes in our response string. After all the headers are done, 
we follow up by adding one more new line, to separate the headers from 
the content we want to print. Again, as part of the HTTP Spec.
  socket.print response
  socket.close
end

Finally, we use that same socket.print method to print our response 
variable. After that&amp;apos;s done, we close the socket.
But does this work? Open up your Terminal just like before, 
and run it with the following command.
ruby web.rb
Once that&amp;apos;s running, open up your browser and connect to the following 
address, replacing username with your Koding Username.
http://hostname.username.koding.io
Congratulations, you&amp;apos;re running a Ruby Web server, with a hand made HTTP 
implementation!
  Installing dependencies with RubyGems This is great and all, but it&amp;apos;s quite the complex way to run a simple web 
server. Lets make this a lot easier with the popular web framework, 
Sinatra.
To use Sinatra, we need to install it. Run the following command to 
install Sinatra with RubyGems.
sudo gem install sinatra
RubyGems is Ruby&amp;apos;s answer to Dependency Management. Similar to NPM and 
PIP, the above command will install Sinatra and all dependencies of that 
library.
Next up, open your web.rb file again, and replace the entire contents 
with the following code.
require &amp;apos;rubygems&amp;apos; # This is required because the http://rubygems.org resource is not included automatically for sinatra to boot
require &amp;apos;sinatra&amp;apos;

set :bind, &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;
set :port, 3000

get &amp;apos;/&amp;apos; do
  &amp;quot;Hello World, from Sinatra!&amp;quot;
end

Now run it just like before, and visit it in your browser. Just like 
that, you have a working Sinatra web server!
In a following tutorial we&amp;apos;ll dig deeper into Sinatra, but for now check 
out the Official Documentation. And as always, Happy Koding!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Installing Linux Dash</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/linux-dash</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-15T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/linux-dash</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Linux Dash is a low-overhead monitoring web dashboard for a GNU/Linux 
machine. With a dead-simple installation and easy to view information, it 
can make viewing an overview of your Linux system a beginner friendly 
endevour. In this guide we&amp;apos;ll go over this two step install process on 
Koding. Lets get started!
  Installation To install dash we simply need download linux-dash from source, and then 
place it into an Apache directory. To do this, run the following 
commands. Note, you can simply copy the entire group of commands and 
paste it into your Terminal. They will execute sequentially.
wget https://github.com/afaqurk/linux-dash/archive/master.zip
unzip master.zip
rm master.zip
mv linux-dash-master ~/Web/dash
That&amp;apos;s it! Dash uses PHP, which means there is no traditional 
installation process. We only need a few things, all of which Koding 
comes with by default!
  Dashboard To access your dashboard, visit your Koding Domain, which will look like 
the following address.
http://hostname.username.koding.io/dash
Where username is your Koding Username. You will see a Dashboard, 
similar to the following image.

That&amp;apos;s all there is to it! Enjoy!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Installing PHP</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-php</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-06T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-php</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>To install the latest version of PHP, use these commands in the Terminal:
sudo apt-get install php5
After that we need a library that will interact with the Apache server. You can install that using the following command.
sudo apt-get install libapache2-mod-php5
Now, you need to restart the Apache server to see the changes.
sudo /etc/init.d/apache2 restart
That is all!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started: Editing Your Profile</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/editing-your-profile</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-04T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/editing-your-profile</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Your Koding profile is your public information page on Koding. Currently 
it shows your Avatar, Name and Description, recent Koding activity, and 
in the near future Badges and additional social information. In this 
guide we&amp;apos;ll go over the basic usage of your Koding profile.
  Getting to your Profile To find your profile, look in the lower left of Koding, as highlighted 
below.

Clicking on it will open your profile.
  Avatar, Name and Description When viewing your profile for the first time, you&amp;apos;ll see that your first 
name is set to your Koding username, and your last name and description 
are set to default values, as seen in the below image.

These default values are only seen by you, and if you double click them, 
you can edit that field.





</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Author a guide: Overview and Guidelines</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/contribute/guidelines</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-04T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/contribute/guidelines</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>When submitting guides to Koding University you must understand the 
document structure, as well as writing styles. Guides on Koding 
University should be formatted in a similar style and tone. This guide 
will outline some guideliness for guide submissions to adhere to.
Note that while these should be taken as best practices more than 
absolute law, submissions may be rejected if they deviate too far from 
the guidelines.
  What is Koding University? Koding University is an Open Source, statically generated site.  Each 
document is stored as Markdown files found in the KDLearn 
Repository. The actual implementation code is hidden in the 
dotfile directory named .metalsmith. We&amp;apos;ll go over this directory in 
the Previewing guide.
  File Structure By keeping the content in the main directory, and hiding the 
implementation, the file structure becomes content first. Meaning 
that at the root of the repo you see the actual content structure. You do 
not need to know how to compile the site, or any real implementation 
details, just write markdown!
As an example, lets look at the markdown file that you&amp;apos;re reading now.If you look at the repo, you&amp;apos;ll see a file named 
contribute/guidelines.md. This file compiles to 
http://learn.koding.com/contribute/guidelines/index.html. Notice how 
the path contribute/guidelines is the same for the source and output 
html? Below are a few more examples.

./contribute/index.md becomes
http://learn.koding.com/contribute/index.html
./guides/markdown.md becomes
http://learn.koding.com/guides/markdown/index.html
./faq/one-more-step.md becomes
http://learn.koding.com/faq/one-more-step/index.html
./guides/your-new-guide.md becomes
http://learn.koding.com/guides/your-new-guide/index.html

See the pattern? Each file can be accessed from the same name on the 
website, minus the .md. ./foo.md becomes /foo on the website.
That means if you add a file, either markdown or image, it will be 
added to the site with the same location relative to the project root.It&amp;apos;s not hidden away in some obscure and complicated file structure, what 
you see in markdown is what shows up on the site. Content first.
  Recommended URL Structure Now that you understand the File Structure and how it correlates to the 
generated URL, we recommend that you adhere to the following naming 
conventions for your document URLs.

Guides should be within the kdlearn/guides directory.
Your filename should describe your guide in clear wording.
Be concise. Try not to have more than 5 words for a filename.
No special characters. Plain words and hyphens only. Example: 
foo-bar-baz.md.

  Title and Description A guide&amp;apos;s title and description are also very important to the document.These will be how people find your guide.
The title is your Markdown Header 1. It should be similar to the URL, 
concise, no more than 7 words.
The description is the first paragraph of your guide, directly following 
the Markdown Header (title). Explain what the guide is about, and what 
the technologies being explained are. Keep it to a single paragraph.
  Headers are awesome, use them. Headers are a great way to separate content sections. They stand out, can 
be linked to directly, and have levels built into them without nesting 
indentation.
These are preferred over ordered lists for larger sections. Ordered lists 
are great for small steps, headers are great for larger steps / 
instructions.
Don&amp;apos;t forget, headers with levels (## Header1, ### Header 3, and so 
forth) should be used to group content just like you do with HTML&amp;apos;s 
&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;s and so forth. You can review Header Markdown here
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Author a guide: Basic</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/contribute/basic</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-04T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/contribute/basic</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll go over how to contribute to the Koding University 
the easy way. We&amp;apos;ll be using Github&amp;apos;s built in editor, to make the 
forking &amp;amp; merging process easy. If you&amp;apos;re unfamiliar with Git, but you 
still want to contribute to Learn, this is the guide for you. So, lets 
get started!
  Edit on Github Each Koding guide comes with a simple &amp;quot;Edit this on Github&amp;quot; link. This 
link directs you back to a file editor on Github. Github will 
automatically fork the repo if you have not yet, and even create a branch 
so that your eventual pull request does not cause any unintended 
contributions. Lets look at how this works.
First up, find the guide that you want to edit, and look for the 
Improve this Guide button at the bottom of all guides.

  Fork the Repository If you have not contributed before you likely do not have the repository 
forked yet. Press the green button seen below, and Github will fork the 
repository for you.

  Make your Edits After forking, or if you already had Koding University Forked, you&amp;apos;ll be 
presented with a text editor for the guide that you chose to edit. From 
here, look through the guide and make your edits as you desire.

Don&amp;apos;t forget that there is a preview tab as well. The guide will look 
slightly different on Github than on Koding University; but because 
everything is formatted in Markdown you can preview it Github to ensure 
the correctness of your markdown syntax.
  Propose File Changes After you have made your edits to the document, scroll down and enter a 
title and description for the edits you&amp;apos;ve made. After you&amp;apos;re satisfied, 
press Propose file change.

This will create a new branch of your Fork and store your changes into 
that branch. To repeat, your changes have been added to your Fork, 
not to the official Koding University repository yet. To do that, you 
need to create a Pull Request.
  Create Pull Request A pull request lets Koding Staff review and merge your changes into the 
official repository. To do that, after proposing your file changes you 
will see a page like the one below.

This is your branch, on your forked repository. If you press the Create 
Pull Request button, your changes in that branch will be sent to the 
official repository to be reviewed and merged in.
This is it! You&amp;apos;ve gone from the guide on University, to editing it and 
submitting your changes for review, all without leaving your browser or 
using any complex Git commands.
  Creating a New Guide The above process is nice and simple, but there&amp;apos;s one core thing missing. 
We didn&amp;apos;t create a guide, we only edited a guide. What if we want to 
create a new guide? Luckily this Basic workflow also works with new 
guides! Lets go over that real quick.
First, click here. That link will send you to the Github 
editor with no file loaded. You can write in the editor, add a file name, 
and propose changes just like the above instructions. Remember to name 
your file with the .md extension, and adhere to the 
Guidelines.
Because you&amp;apos;re creating a new file though, you want to make sure and add 
the proper metadata to the file. Copy the following code, and place it 
into the editor.
---
author: Your Name
username: yourUsername
date: 2014-07-31
categories: [nginx]
---

Fill in Your Name with your name, and yourUsername with your Koding 
Username. The date field should be formatted in YYYY-MM-DD format, and 
the categories list is just a comma separated list of strings.

Once that&amp;apos;s all taken care of, start writing your guide! Once you&amp;apos;re 
done, follow the Propose and Pull Request instructions above, as they are 
identical.
You should note that with this method, you cannot add images to the 
repository. For that to work, have a look at the next section which uses 
Koding&amp;apos;s Editor and Git to make changes to this Koding University.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started with Python</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-python</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-04T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-python</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll go over explaining what Python is, how to use Python 
Packaging via the PIP command, and how to write your first Python web 
server using a small library known as Flask. So, lets get started!
  What is Python Python is a popular, general purpose, high level programing language. It 
focuses on readability programmer sanity over raw performance. Python2 
and Python3 come pre-installed on Koding VMs, and in this guide we&amp;apos;re 
going to focus on Python2. Lets see what it looks like to run some python 
code!
  Running your first Python script Open up your Ace Editor create a new file named hello.py. Paste 
in the following code into that file.
print &amp;quot;Hello from python!&amp;quot;

The print keyword takes a string and prints it to the Standard Output 
(STDOUT) of the process. Lets try running this file so we can see this 
output, but first save the file with Ctrl-s.  Now, open up your 
Terminal and type in the following command.
python hello.py
You should see output similar to this:
joshmurray: ~ $ python hello.py
Hello from python!
joshmurray: ~ $
Neat! Lets take this a couple steps further, and do something actually 
useful, lets run a web server! But first, lets get to know Pip, and 
install a library that makes making python Web Applications easy!
  Installing Pip pip is a popular Python Package Manager. However, we need to install it 
onto our Koding VM to use it. To do that, we&amp;apos;re going to use AptGet, with 
the following command.
sudo apt-get install python-pip
Give that a moment, and once that finishes we can install Flask!
  Using Pip to install Flask You may be wondering why we&amp;apos;re using Flask to write this little web 
server of ours. Flask has a really nice API for making compact web 
applications.  This is great for a beginner guide, since we can look at a 
few core concepts without getting too bogged down with technical details 
of a web server.
Now that you have pip installed, to install Flask type the following 
command.
sudo pip install Flask
Note that we&amp;apos;re using sudo because the default location for the 
installed packages is in a root directory. A common practice to store 
these without root permissions is to use a Virtual Environment to keep 
your packages installed per-project. We&amp;apos;ll save that for a later guide 
though.
Once that finishes installing, lets write our Flask code!
  Creating your first Flask web server Create a new file named web.py, and paste in the following code.
from flask import Flask
app = Flask(__name__)

@app.route(&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;)
def hello():
    return &amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;

if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;:
    app.run(host=&amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;)

There are a few interesting points in this source though, so before we 
run our web server, lets go over the source.
from flask import Flask

First up are our from and import keywords. The import imports a 
module to an object with the same name. When used with the from keyword 
though, only the Flask object is imported to the current scope. So, 
this line imports a function named Flask.
app = Flask(__name__)

Next up, we use that Flask() function to create a Flask instance, 
stored in the name app.
__name__ is a special keyword which stores the name of the currently 
module, or it equals &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot; if run directly. We&amp;apos;ll see this again 
at the end of the script.
def hello():
    return &amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;

We&amp;apos;re skipping a line, and going straight to the def keyword. This is 
how we define a function in Python. In this case, we&amp;apos;re using this 
function as a handler for our Flask &amp;quot;route&amp;quot;.
@app.route(&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;)
def hello():
    return &amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;

If we look at that function again, including the line we skipped, we see 
a new syntax structure, @app.route(&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;).
This is known as a Decorator. Decorators are a special syntax for a 
function wrapping another function. If you&amp;apos;re new to programming, this 
can be a bit of a tricky concept which involves Higher Order 
Functions. We&amp;apos;ll briefly touch this below, but for now we&amp;apos;ll just 
take it at face value. This is how Flask routes our request to our 
handler.
A Route is a concept that directs requests (people viewing your web 
server) and routes them to your Handler functions. &amp;quot;/&amp;quot; is the path 
for this route, meaning that when someone connects to 
http://hostname.username.koding.io/ they are given this function.
If someone connected to http://hostname.username.koding.io/foo/bar, it 
would not return this handler, because /foo/bar does not match our 
hello route.
if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;:
    app.run(host=&amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;)

Finally we&amp;apos;re at the end of the script. If you remember the __name__ 
keyword from before, remember that it holds the name of the current 
module. If the file is run directly from Python though, ie python 
web.py, then the value is &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;.
By writing a __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot; condition, we make it so that if 
this file is run directly it will start the web server. If the file is 
imported though, it will not. This is great because we don&amp;apos;t want 
imports to execute a bunch of potentially dangerous code. Good 
programming practice.
  Running our Flask web server Now that we have looked at the source, lets run this thing! We can run 
this file just like above, with..
python web.py
And then connect to it with the following address.
http://hostname.username.koding.io:5000
Flask will display our text when you request the root path, awesome!
  Decorators Briefly Explained Now that we&amp;apos;ve gone through the web server source, lets revisit the 
Decorators and go into a bit more depth. We won&amp;apos;t go over every concept 
in full detail, so that we can keep this a sanely short beginner 
tutorial, and not a book.
To help explain decorators, lets add our own Decorator.
def from_py(hello):
  def wrapper(*args, **kwargs):
    return hello(*args, **kwargs) + &amp;quot; From Python!&amp;quot;
  return wrapper

@app.route(&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;)
@from_py
def hello():
    return &amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;

Lets analyze this.
from_py is simply a function, that takes another function. When we add 
the keyword before of a function def, from_py is called with that 
function as the first argument. This &amp;quot;wraps&amp;quot; hello() with our 
from_py() function.
Next, we create a new function inside the from_py function that acts as a handler.
The (*args, **kwargs) 
parameters is a special syntax to keep all of the given arguments in 
those two objects, so that we can fully pass them to the hello() 
handler.
In our wrapper function, we then call then hello() function, with 
the arguments given to wrapper().
When hello() returns, we add our own string &amp;quot; From Python!&amp;quot;, and 
return that as well.
So that means
@app.route(&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;)
@from_py
def hello():
    return &amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;

Is actually many functions, more than three. We could write out the 
entire structure here, but just focus on the @from_py for now, as to 
avoid being confused by a huge group of nested functions.
If this still doesn&amp;apos;t make sense, don&amp;apos;t worry! Higher order functions can 
take some getting used to. Practice them, and make your own, they&amp;apos;re well 
worth understanding!
  Python2 vs Python3 Finally, a Python talk is never complete without wrapping everything up 
in a big Python2 vs Python3 debate! .. Luckily, we won&amp;apos;t do that here.
If you&amp;apos;re new to Python, and unsure which version to use, it doesn&amp;apos;t 
really matter. They&amp;apos;re both quite similar, pick one, and learn it. Once 
you learn one, the other version will be easily usable, and you&amp;apos;ll be 
able to spot the differences with ease.
Python3 is the eventual future, but it&amp;apos;s taken many years to gain 
traction, and will take many more. Choosing which to use can be a hard 
decision for seasoned programmers wanting to write large code bases. You 
shouldn&amp;apos;t worry about that, currently. Save that for another day :)
This concludes the getting started with Python guide. Thanks for reading!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Author a guide: Previewing</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/contribute/previewing</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-04T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/contribute/previewing</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>While you shouldn&amp;apos;t need to preview your guides, since Markdown is 
designed to be human friendly in the source, if you insist you can 
preview your guides as they are on Koding University. This guide will go 
over that process. Note that this will require a bit of developer 
know-how, so be prepared to get your hands dirty. Lets get started!
  Requirements You will need a working NodeJS installation to compile the Koding 
University source. If you do not, visit the NodeJS downloads 
page and grab the installer.
  Installation With a working NodeJS installation, we need to install the KU 
dependencies, as well as a global installation of the GulpJS. This can be 
done with the following code:
npm install -g gulp
cd .metalsmith
npm install
  Building With Gulp installed, simply run the following command, to compile the 
entire project into HTML.
(Ignore cd .metalsmtih if you&amp;apos;re already in that directory)
cd .metalsmith
gulp
The .metalsmith/build directory will contain all of the compiled html, 
css, and any static resources (such as images/etc) from the markdown 
directory.
Compiling can take 1-2 minutes, so be patient.
  Previewing If you want to preview the compiled site, open a new Koding Terminal tab 
and run the following:
(Ignore cd .metalsmtih if you&amp;apos;re already in that directory)
cd .metalsmith
gulp preview
This will run a small HTTP Server on Port 8000, ie: 
http://hostname.you.koding.io:8000. Keep this tab open, and in  a 
different Koding Terminal tab run your gulp command from above.Each time you compile the site, this will show your compiled site.
  Compiling as you type To have your Markdown compiled as you write your documents, run the 
following commands:
(Ignore cd .metalsmtih if you&amp;apos;re already in that directory)
cd .metalsmith
gulp watch
This, in combination with the preview command above, will compile the 
site each time you change the Markdown.
Note that if you add images for your guide to use, you&amp;apos;ll want to run the 
full gulp command again.
And that sums it up! You now know how to contribute to Koding University, 
in multiple ways. Keep up the awesome work, and we look forward to your 
contribution!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Author a guide</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/contribute</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-04T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/contribute</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide series we will go over Writing and Editing guides for Koding 
University. We will cover every step of the process, but basic Git, 
Github, and Markdown knowledge will be very useful.
If you already know git, github, and markdown, here is the simple set of 
tasks you&amp;apos;ll need to do.

Review the Style Guidelines
Fork KDLearn
Clone your forked repo
Find or create your files, Make your markdown edits
Commit and push your changes to your repo
Make a pull request of your changes, against the KDLearn Repo

If you need more in depth instructions than that, please continue with 
this series below. Thanks!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started with ExpressJS</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-expressjs</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-02T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-expressjs</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we will go over basic usage of the NodeJS web framework, 
ExpressJS. If you are not familiar with NodeJS, please review the 
Getting Started with NodeJS guide. Lets get 
started!
  Installing First, make a directory to follow along with this tutorial, and work from 
in that directory. Next, we&amp;apos;re going to install Express with the 
following command.
npm install express
If you already have a package.json file for your project, you can add 
the --save flag and Express will be added as a project dependency. In 
this example we&amp;apos;re going to ignore dependencies for simplicity.
You&amp;apos;ll notice a new directory is created named node_modules. This is 
where the local installations of your packages are stored. When you 
import them, such as with require(&amp;apos;express&amp;apos;), they are loaded from this 
directory.
  Hello World and Routes Copy the following code into a file named app.js. Remember that at 
anytime you can run your server with node app.js.
var express = require(&amp;apos;express&amp;apos;);
var app     = express();

app.get(&amp;apos;/&amp;apos;, function(req, res){
  res.send(&amp;apos;Hello World, From /&amp;apos;);
});
app.get(&amp;apos;/:name&amp;apos;, function(req, res){
  res.send(&amp;apos;Hello &amp;apos;+ req.params.name);
});

var server = app.listen(3000, &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;, function() {
  console.log(&amp;apos;Listening on port %d&amp;apos;, server.address().port);
});

Lets go over each section real quick.
app.get(&amp;apos;/&amp;apos;, function(req, res){
  res.send(&amp;apos;Hello World, From /&amp;apos;);
});
app.get(&amp;apos;/:name&amp;apos;, function(req, res){
  res.send(&amp;apos;Hello &amp;apos;+ req.params.name);
});

The app.get() method takes a Route (string or regex) to listen to 
requests on. If a user visits http://hostname.username.koding.io/, they 
are greeted with Hello World, From /.
If someone visits http://hostname.username.koding.io/john, they are 
greeted with Hello john. :name is a URL parameter, which is sort of 
like a wildcard for that section of the URL. Respond to the request with 
the parameter by using the name of the parameter on the req.params 
object.
var server = app.listen(3000, &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;, function() {
  console.log(&amp;apos;Listening on port %d&amp;apos;, server.address().port);
});

This final call simply starts the web server on 0.0.0.0:3000.
  Middleware We saw how to run a simple server, with a couple routes, now lets add a 
bit of middleware.
Middleware is a concept of a function which is called in the middle of 
the request cycle. It&amp;apos;s useful for rejecting non-authorized users to many 
routes, logging, or just about anything. Middleware is pretty awesome.
Lets add our own middleware to simply log all requests to the console, 
and another to log all /:name requests from above.
app.use(function(req, res, next) {
  console.log(&amp;apos;[&amp;apos;+ new Date() +&amp;apos;] &amp;apos;, req.path);
  next();
});

var logName = function(req, res, next) {
  console.log(&amp;apos;Request to &amp;apos;+ req.params.name);
  next();
}

We&amp;apos;ve defined two middleware functions above. Our logging function is 
first, and we immediately pass it to app.use(). Every request that this 
express application receives will first go through this logging function.The logging function just logs the date time, and the path of the 
request. Note the next() callback, that tells Express that this 
middleware is done, and the next one can be called.
Our second middleware, logName, is not being used yet. Why? Well, we 
only want to use this for our /:name route, because it&amp;apos;s supposed to 
log names. How can we achieve this though? Lets take a look at our 
/:name route, with the middleware added.
app.get(&amp;apos;/:name&amp;apos;, logName, function(req, res){
  res.send(&amp;apos;Hello &amp;apos;+ req.params.name);
});

By adding this middleware to our route, every request to /:name will 
first pass through our logName function, and then the final anonymous 
function to handle the full response.
Lets look at the full code at this state.
var express = require(&amp;apos;express&amp;apos;);
var app     = express();

app.use(function(req, res, next) {
  console.log(&amp;apos;[&amp;apos;+ new Date() +&amp;apos;] &amp;apos;, req.path);
  next();
});

var logName = function(req, res, next) {
  console.log(&amp;apos;Request to &amp;apos;+ req.params.name);
  next();
}

app.get(&amp;apos;/&amp;apos;, function(req, res){
  res.send(&amp;apos;Hello World, From /&amp;apos;);
});
app.get(&amp;apos;/:name&amp;apos;, logName, function(req, res){
  res.send(&amp;apos;Hello &amp;apos;+ req.params.name);
});

var server = app.listen(3000, &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;, function() {
  console.log(&amp;apos;Listening on port %d&amp;apos;, server.address().port);
});

Note: It&amp;apos;s important to remember that order of execution matters! If 
we define a piece of middleware after a route, requests to that route 
will not run through that middleware. In the above example, the very 
first thing we do is declare our app.use() middleware, and in the 
/:name middleware we use the logName function before our handler.
  Adding Templates Now we&amp;apos;re getting a hang of routes and middleware, lets complete the step 
and add in a template. Add the following code to the top of your app.js 
file.
app.set(&amp;apos;view engine&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;jade&amp;apos;);
app.set(&amp;apos;views&amp;apos;, __dirname + &amp;apos;/views&amp;apos;);

app.set() is used to configure this app instance. In this case, we set 
a couple templating settings of Express, to use the Jade templating 
language from the ./views directory.
Next, create a directory named views, and add the following code to a 
file named index.jade
doctype
html
  head
    title Hello #{name}
  body
    h1 Hello #{name}

We won&amp;apos;t go over the Jade language here, but in short #{name} is a 
variable which is being passed to this template when we render it. If 
you&amp;apos;re paying attention, you&amp;apos;ll notice that we have yet to actually 
render a template in our requests. Lets add the above template to our 
/:name handler!
app.get(&amp;apos;/:name&amp;apos;, logName, function(req, res){
  res.render(&amp;apos;index&amp;apos;, {name: req.params.name});
});

In our /:name handler, we&amp;apos;ve replaced the res.send() call with 
res.render(). This loads our index.jade template and renders it, with 
the object we&amp;apos;re passing in as data. The name property of that object 
is accessible from the jade template!
  The final product Lets take one final look at all of this app.js code together.
var express = require(&amp;apos;express&amp;apos;);
var app     = express();

// Set our view engine to Jade, and the view directory
app.set(&amp;apos;view engine&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;jade&amp;apos;);
app.set(&amp;apos;views&amp;apos;, __dirname + &amp;apos;/views&amp;apos;);

// Enable our custom Logging middleware
app.use(function(req, res, next) {
  console.log(&amp;apos;[&amp;apos;+ new Date() +&amp;apos;] &amp;apos;, req.path);
  next();
});

// Our logName middleware, which can be used in any route we want.
var logName = function(req, res, next) {
  console.log(&amp;apos;Request to &amp;apos;+ req.params.name);
  next();
}

// Our two routes and handlers
app.get(&amp;apos;/&amp;apos;, function(req, res){
  res.send(&amp;apos;Hello World, From /&amp;apos;);
});
app.get(&amp;apos;/:name&amp;apos;, logName, function(req, res){
  res.render(&amp;apos;index&amp;apos;, {name: req.params.name});
});

// Finally, start our web server.
var server = app.listen(3000, &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;, function() {
  console.log(&amp;apos;Listening on port %d&amp;apos;, server.address().port);
});

Run the above code with node app.js, and visit
http://hostname.username.koding.io/Josh
And you&amp;apos;ll see an html page, rendered from your awesome new Express app!
And that&amp;apos;s it! We&amp;apos;ve gone through what express is, how to set it up, 
routes, middleware, and finally templates. Thanks for reading!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started with NodeJS</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-nodejs</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-01T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started-nodejs</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll go over explaining what NodeJS is, what it can do, 
and how to write your first NodeJS web server on Koding. We&amp;apos;ll be 
approaching everything from a beginners perspective. So, lets get 
started!
  What is NodeJS NodeJS, commonly called Node, is a program which runs JavaScript code on 
a computer. This is similar to your browser, except instead of having 
access to the Document Object Model (DOM) and HTML5 APIs, it has access 
to a Node specific API which gives you access to the file system, and raw 
networking.
JavaScript run in Node is very similar to Python or Ruby. You have a 
command node, which runs some JavaScript code. This code uses the Node 
API to modify the file system, or send/receive network packets. It&amp;apos;s 
rather low level by itself, but like all major languages people have 
built frameworks ontop of the raw API to make it easier to create 
applications.
  Installing NodeJS and NPM By default every Koding VM comes preinstalled with NodeJS and NPM, but in case you somehow removed it you can use the following commands to get it back.
To install it use the following command:
sudo apt-get install nodejs
If the above should fail you can install NodeJS through a PPA repository like so:
sudo apt-get install python-software-properties  
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:chris-lea/node.js  
sudo apt-get update  
sudo apt-get install nodejs
You can check the NodeJS version and if it installed correctly, after the installation process has finished, using the following command:
nodejs -v
You will also need the Node Packaged Modules or NPM. To install NPM, simply run the following command:
sudo apt-get install npm
To make sure NPM has installed successfully, run:
npm -v
  Running your first Node Script Lets setup a single print line script, and call it. Open up your Ace 
editor, and open up a new file by pressing the Plus Button on the 
tab list. If your file says Untitled.txt, you&amp;apos;re good to go.
Next, paste the following code into a new script.
console.log(&amp;apos;Hello from NodeJS!&amp;apos;)

If you&amp;apos;re familiar with Web Development, you&amp;apos;ll likely notice that this 
line if code is identical to what you could use in your Browser. You can 
copy this code and run it in your Browser Console right now! This works, 
because the JavaScript running in Node is just javascript. No 
modifications to the language have been made. The differences come when 
we start using the Node API, which we&amp;apos;ll see when we run our web server 
below.
Before we run a web server though, lets see the output of our script.  We 
haven&amp;apos;t saved our file yet though, so use Ctrl-S to save the file, 
and name it hello.js. Finally, open up the Koding Terminal 
and run this file with the following code.
node hello.js
You should see output similar to this:
joshmurray: ~ $ node hello.js
Hello from NodeJS!
joshmurray: ~ $
Not surprisingly, it printed our console.log() output! Next up, lets 
get out feet wet with a little bit of the API known as the http 
library.
  Running your first Node Web Server var http = require(&amp;apos;http&amp;apos;);

var server = http.createServer(function(req, res) {
  res.end(&amp;apos;Hello from NodeJS!\n&amp;apos;);
  console.log(&amp;apos;Someone visited our web server!&amp;apos;);
})

server.listen(3000, &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;);
console.log(&amp;quot;NodeJS web server running on 0.0.0.0:3000&amp;quot;);

Just like in the steps above, open a new file, paste in the above code, 
and save it as web.js. Lets break down this code piece by piece before 
we run it.
var http = require(&amp;apos;http&amp;apos;);

This line is how NodeJS &amp;quot;Imports&amp;quot; modules. Each NodeJS file is considered 
a module, and can be imported by specifying the file location relative to 
the path of the current file.
Eg, require(&amp;apos;./foo&amp;apos;) would import a file named foo.js in the current 
directory. require(&amp;apos;./foo/bar&amp;apos;) would import a file named bar.js in 
the foo directory.
You should note that there is a difference between our relative imports, 
and the http import above. If you install a library with npm, or use 
built-in libraries like http, you do not need to specify the path. Node 
will look up your file path until the package is found, or return an 
error if it fails to find it. http is part of the Standard Library, so 
of course it is found.
After require(&amp;apos;http&amp;apos;) loads the module, we store it in a variable named 
http
var server = http.createServer(function(req, res) {

Here, we call a function createServer on the http module. I won&amp;apos;t go 
into too much detail of the usage of function, but in short it takes a 
function and passes in a Request and Response object to the function. For 
further reading, checkout the documentation on 
createServer().
This function creates a web server, stored in server in our example.Each time a request comes in to our server, our function is called with 
the req (Request) and res (Response) of the current request. We 
can get information about the request, and create a response for the 
requester.
  res.end(&amp;apos;Hello from NodeJS!\n&amp;apos;);
  console.log(&amp;apos;Someone visited our web server!&amp;apos;);

In this example, we&amp;apos;re calling res.end() to end the current request. We 
pass in a string, to be given to the client.
We also make a console.log() call, so that in our Terminal we can see 
when people request our web server.
server.listen(3000, &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;);
console.log(&amp;quot;NodeJS web server running on 0.0.0.0:3000&amp;quot;);

Finally, we call the server.listen() function. This takes a port, and 
an IP to listen on. When called, it starts the server we defined above.Meaning that any requests that are made to that address (relative to the 
machine), 0.0.0.0:3000 calls our above function, which we then end 
with Hello from NodeJS!.
Lets try this out now, and run it. Just like before, with the file saved 
type node web.js (remember, we named this one web.js). Once it&amp;apos;s 
running, open up your browser and go to
http://hostname.username.koding.io:3000
Where username is your Koding Username.
After you visit your that address, you should see a simple web response 
with the Hello from NodeJS! string. If you then go back to the 
Terminal, you&amp;apos;ll see that the server logged a visit. If you refresh your 
web page a few times, you can watch your web server respond to each 
request!
NodeJS web server running on 0.0.0.0:3000
Someone visited our web server!
This sums up the Getting Started with NodeJS guide. You should now have a 
good understanding of what Node is, from a very basic perspective. As 
always, don&amp;apos;t forget to look at the API Documentation. Have 
fun with Node!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Ghost Blog Installation</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/ghost-installation</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-08-01T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/ghost-installation</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this article we will go over the installation process for the awesome 
new blogging software, Ghost. Installation is quick 
and easy, and just requires a few configuration edits, making this great 
for beginners. So, lets get started!
  What is Ghost? Ghost is an awesome new blog software written with &amp;#x201C;Just Blogging&amp;#x201D; in 
mind. Think WordPress without the complexity, bringing blogging back to 
it&amp;#x2019;s roots, so to say. This is all well and good, but with any product 
that is so new there is always confusion on how to install, develop, and 
run it.
So lets try and resolve some of that confusion. Lets go over the simple 
process of setting up Ghost on Koding so you can 
learn it, toy with it, develop with it, and create your Ghost blog to be 
exactly what you want.
  Downloading Ghost We&amp;apos;re going to use the Koding Terminal to download Ghost, so 
visit the [Ghost Download][download-page] and look for the download link.Copy the url.
At the time of writing this guide, the download url is: 
https://ghost.org/zip/ghost-0.5.2.zip (This version is likely 
outdated, please visit the download page and get the most updated link.)
Now, go to your Terminal and type in the following commands.
mkdir ghost
cd ghost
wget [ghost-zip-url]
Replace [ghost-zip-url] with the full URL of the zip file that you 
copied above.
  Unzipping Ghost The download is in zip format, so we need to unzip it. Type in the 
following command.
unzip [ghost-zip-name]
  Installing Dependencies Next, we need to install the dependencies.
npm install --production
This step will take a minute or two.
  Edit the config Next up, open up the Ace Editor and double click your ghost 
directory to expand it. Right click, and rename, the config.example.js 
file to config.js.
On line 36, look for the following section:
        server: {
            // Host to be passed to node&amp;apos;s `net.Server#listen()`
            host: &amp;apos;127.0.0.1&amp;apos;,
            // Port to be passed to node&amp;apos;s `net.Server#listen()`, for 
iisnode set this to `process.env.PORT`
            port: &amp;apos;2368&amp;apos;
        },

Replace 127.0.0.1 with 0.0.0.0, and change the Port to whichever 
you&amp;apos;d like to use. Save the file with Ctrl-s.
  Starting Ghost Go back to your Terminal and type in the following command to 
start your Ghost Blog.
npm start
Note: If you had previously closed your Terminal, you&amp;apos;ll need to navigate 
into the ghost directory again, with cd ghost.
  Visiting your Ghost Blog Now open up a new tab and visit your Ghost Blog on your Koding domain at 
the following address.
http://hostname.username.koding.io:port
Where username is your Koding username, and port is the port you 
chose above.
If you navigate to the following address, you can signup as Admin to your 
Ghost installation.
http://hostname.username.koding.io:port/ghost
  Running Ghost on Port 80 If you&amp;apos;d like to run Ghost on the default Port 80, you&amp;apos;ll have to Stop 
Apache, and start Ghost with sudo. Here are the commands to do this.
sudo service apache2 stop
sudo npm start
This should be typed from the Ghost installation directory.
And that&amp;apos;s it! You should now have a Ghost installation up and running.Happy Blogging!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Installing Nginx</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/nginx</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-31T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/nginx</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Nginx is an open source proxy server, commonly used as a replace
Nginx is an open source web server. Built with performance and memory usage in 
mind, it&amp;apos;s an excellent alternative to Apache. In this guide, we&amp;apos;ll go through 
the simple process of installing Nginx on Koding. Lets get started!
  Installing Nginx Koding runs Ubuntu, gives you root, and of course comes with apt-get. This 
means that installation of many packages, programs and servers simply 
require using apt-get. To install Nginx with apt-get, run the following 
command.
sudo apt-get install nginx
Confirm the installation by pressing enter at the [Y/n] prompt, and proceed 
to the next step.
  Starting Nginx Your Virtual Machine comes with Apache preinstalled and configured. It&amp;apos;s 
what serves up the web page that you see when you visit 
http://hostname.username.koding.io. So before we start Nginx, we have 
to stop Apache with the following command.
sudo service apache2 stop
You can then start your Nginx server by using the following command.
sudo service nginx start
If you now visit your User (or VM) domain at 
http://hostname.username.koding.io, you&amp;apos;ll see a welcome to nginx page 
like the one below. This means your Nginx server is up and running.

  Using ~/Web Your Nginx server is running, but it&amp;apos;s not serving up the files that you expect 
from your ~/Web directory. To do this we need to edit out 
/etc/nginx/sites-available/default file with a Terminal editor such as Nano 
or Vim. In this example we&amp;apos;ll use Nano for simplicity.
Open up your Terminal and run the following command.
sudo nano /etc/nginx/sites-available/default
You&amp;apos;ll see a bunch of green text, similar to the following image. What we&amp;apos;re 
looking to edit is the text root /usr/share/nginx/html, as seen highlighted 
in this image:

Using your arrow keys, navigate to the end of the /usr/share/nginx/html text 
and delete the entire folder name (with your backspace key). Replace it with 
the folder /var/www.
    root /var/www
By doing this, you&amp;apos;re changing the directory of files that nginx is serving by 
default. /var/www is the default Apache dir, and is soft-linked to ~/Web. 
In short, we&amp;apos;re telling Nginx to use what we currently use.
After you&amp;apos;ve made the appropriate edits, use Ctrl-X to close Nano. You&amp;apos;ll be 
prompted with a Y/n question to save the file. Type y. Next you&amp;apos;ll be 
prompted for the filename to save it, press Enter, as the filename field is 
already filled out.
Now all we have to do is restart our web server!
sudo service nginx restart
If you visit your domain again you&amp;apos;ll see the same ~/Web files that you are 
familiar with. You now have an Nginx server up and running, and serving your 
Web files. Enjoy!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Installing MySQL</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-mysql</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-30T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-mysql</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Before you continue reading this guide why not try a more easy way using the Koding Package Manager (kpm) and install mySQL using just one command:
kpm install mysql

In this guide we will cover the basics on how you can install MySQL and 
the latest version of PHP-MySQL modules on your Koding VM.
  Installation via apt-get First open up your Koding IDE and paste the following command into 
your Terminal. This will ensure that your apt-get 
database is at the latest level. 
sudo apt-get update
Now, type in the command below to install mysql, and it&amp;apos;s dependencies.
sudo apt-get install mysql-server mysql-common mysql-client
As part of the installation process, you&amp;apos;ll be presented with the 
following screen.

This is to create your MySQL Root user passphrase. Enter a passphrase 
of your choice, and repeat it at the next screen.
  Logging into MySQL Afterwards, you can confirm your installation by running the following 
command.
mysql -u root -p
When prompted, enter the MySQL root user passphrase that you created 
above.
  PHP MySQL Extensions (Optional) A popular addition to this installation process, are the PHP extensions 
needed to use MySQL form PHP. This is optional, and if you don&amp;apos;t use PHP, 
you can ignore these.
To install the PHP MySQL Extension, simply run the following command.
sudo apt-get install php5-mysql
After that, you&amp;apos;ll need to restart Apache to make use of this extension.This can be done with the following command.
sudo service apache2 restart
That&amp;apos;s it!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Apache Tomcat On Koding</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/apache-tomcat-on-koding</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-29T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/apache-tomcat-on-koding</guid>
    <author>Vinay Jain</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll take a look on how to deploy Java Web Applications on Apache Tomcat Server running on your Koding Virtual Machine.
Since you are here I assume that you already know what Web Applications are and why do you need Apache Tomcat to run those applications.
Tomcat doesn&amp;apos;t come preinstalled with your VMs, so you need do download, install and configure Tomcat manually. Follow the steps below to get started :-
Go to the Terminal, and download tomcat 7.0 using the wget command.
wget http://apache.mirrors.hoobly.com/tomcat/tomcat-7/v7.0.55/bin/apache-tomcat-7.0.55.tar.gz  
If the above link doesn&amp;apos;t work, make sure you get the link from the tomcat&amp;apos;s download page. 
Extract the downloaded file by typing :-
tar -xvzf apache-tomcat-7*
Rename the directory for easy access in future.
mv apache-tomcat-7.0.55 tomcat
Now we need to set role and password in tomcat-users.xml . Use the command below to edit the tomcat-user.xml.
nano apache/conf/tomcat-users.xml
Add these lines just above &amp;lt;/tomcat-users&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;user name=&amp;quot;anyusername&amp;quot; password=&amp;quot;anypassword&amp;quot; roles=&amp;quot;admin-gui,manager-gui&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
Since we have apache server (for PHP) running on our VM on port 80, we must specify another running port for tomcat. So we will edit  server.xml file now. Use the command below to open it in nano.
nano apache/conf/server.xml
Find this line
&amp;lt;Connector port=&amp;quot;8080&amp;quot; protocol=&amp;quot;HTTP/1.1&amp;quot; ....&amp;gt;
Change the port number to 8084
Everything is setup now. Its time to run tomcat.
bash tomcat/bin/startup.sh
If you see Tomcat Started message, you can now open the localhost by typing in the address bar :-
`your_koding_domain:8084` , for me its 
hostname.vinayjain.koding.io:8084
Click on the manager app button and enter your username and password you set in tomcat-users.xml.
Congratulations, you have Apache Tomcat up and running on your Koding VM. Deploy the .war file of your Java app in tomcat and run it.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>What is Bitbucket?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/using-bitbucket-on-koding</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-16T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/using-bitbucket-on-koding</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Bitbucket provides Git and Mercurial hosting for teams.
Host your code online in as many public and private repositories as you want. Free five-user tier accounts!
Manage your projects with confidence with built-in issue trackers, wikis, code comments, and pull requests.
  Setup SSH for Git If you already have ssh keys, then please skip this step.
Please follow this excellent guide by Atlassian on how to setup
ssh keys. 
  Selecting a Repository from Bitbucket Now that you have setup ssh, it is time select a repository from Bitbucket.
When signing into Bitbucket you will be presented with a list of repositories.
For this guide I am going to choose the codemirror repository

  Getting the SSH Clone Url In the repository dashboard you will see a panel in the upper right corner.
Set the url to ssh and copy the url.

  Clone the Repository Good Job so far! Now lets clone the repository into your ~ folder
$ git clone git@bitbucket.org:bvallelunga/codemirror.git
Once git is finished cloning, your terminal will look like this
$ git clone git@bitbucket.org:bvallelunga/codemirror.git
Cloning into &amp;apos;codemirror&amp;apos;...
Enter passphrase for key &amp;apos;/home/bvallelunga/.ssh/id_rsa&amp;apos;: 
remote: Counting objects: 13109, done.                                                                                                                                                                       
remote: Compressing objects: 100% (5060/5060), done.                                                                                                                                                         
remote: Total 13109 (delta 8025), reused 13109 (delta 8025)                                                                                                                                                  
Receiving objects: 100% (13109/13109), 2.78 MiB | 717 KiB/s, done.
Resolving deltas: 100% (8025/8025), done.
  Verify the Repository Exists The last step is to verify that the cloning proccess was successful.
To do this, get the directory listing and check to see if your intended folder exists.
$ ls
Applications  codemirror  Documents  Uploads  Web
As you can see, the codemirror folder exists. Thank you and have a wonderful Koding day!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Drupal Setup and Installation for Beginners</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/php-cms/drupal/setup</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-15T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/php-cms/drupal/setup</guid>
    <author>Thien</author>
    <description>This article will cover the basic steps on how to setup a blog using 
Drupal.
  What&amp;apos;s Drupal? Drupal is a content management system (also refered to as CMS), meaning Drupal is used to manage content on informational sites, social media sites, member sites, intranets and web applications.
But how do you set up Drupal on Koding? Well it&amp;apos;s simple, you just follow the simple tutorial below step by step. After you&amp;apos;ve finished with the tutorial you&amp;apos;ll have a brand new website that runs Drupal.
  Step-by-step Drupal   Step 1. Open up your Koding Terminal and type in the following command to get started.
cd Web
  Step 2. Next up, you must download Drupal version that you&amp;apos;re planing on using, in this case we are going to use Drupal 8
wget http://ftp.drupal.org/files/projects/drupal-8.x-dev.tar.gz
  Step 3. Extracting Drupal, type the following command (replacing &amp;quot;x.x&amp;quot; with your downloaded version&amp;apos;s number):
tar zxvf drupal-8.x-dev.tar.gz  &amp;amp;&amp;amp; rm -rf drupal-8.x-dev.tar.gz
  Step 4. Moving Drupal to its intended location
  Step 5 In order to Drupal working on Nginx, open up the default virtual host(block) file.
sudo vi /etc/nginx/sites-available/default
The configuration should include the changes below (the details of the changes are under the config information):
    server {

        listen   80;
      server_name hostname.duythien.koding.io;

        index index.php index.html index.htm;
        set $root_path &amp;apos;/home/duythien/Web/drupal-8.x-dev&amp;apos;;
        root $root_path;

        gzip_static on;

        location = /favicon.ico {
                log_not_found off;
                access_log off;
        }

        location = /robots.txt {
                allow all;
                log_not_found off;
                access_log off;
        }

        # Very rarely should these ever be accessed outside of your lan
        location ~* \.(txt|log)$ {
                allow 192.168.0.0/16;
                deny all;
        }
        location ~ \..*/.*\.php$ {
                return 403;
        }

        # No no for private
        location ~ ^/sites/.*/private/ {
                return 403;
        }

        # Block access to &amp;quot;hidden&amp;quot; files and directories whose names begin with a
        # period. This includes directories used by version control systems such
        # as Subversion or Git to store control files.
        location ~ (^|/)\. {
                return 403;
        }

        location / {
                # This is cool because no php is touched for static content
                try_files $uri @rewrite;
        }
        location @rewrite {
            # You have 2 options here
            # For D7 and above:
            # Clean URLs are handled in drupal_environment_initialize().
            rewrite ^ /index.php;
            # For Drupal 6 and bwlow:
            # Some modules enforce no slash (/) at the end of the URL
            # Else this rewrite block wouldn&amp;apos;t be needed (GlobalRedirect)
            #rewrite ^/(.*)$ /index.php?q=$1;
        }
        location ~ \.php$ {
            try_files $uri =404;
            fastcgi_split_path_info ^(.+\.php)(/.+)$;
            fastcgi_pass unix:/var/run/php5-fpm.sock;
            fastcgi_index index.php;
            fastcgi_param  SCRIPT_FILENAME  $document_root$fastcgi_script_name;
            include fastcgi_params;
        }
    }
Save and Exit. If you want to run Drupal on Apache, you need to edit the Apache configuration file configuration Apache
sudo vi /etc/apache2/sites-available/default
Then you&amp;apos;ll need to create the database for Drupal, by running the following code.
    echo &amp;apos;CREATE DATABASE drupal8&amp;apos; | mysql -u root
If you haven&amp;apos;t installed MySQL, head on over to this tutorial 
here. If everything goes fine, you should see 
the following screen in your browser:

If you see this error  Writable (public download method), you need to run following code in the command line.
``
 cd $ROOT/site        #/var/www/drupal-8.x-dev/sites
 sudo chmod a+w -R default 
```
That&amp;apos;s it! You&amp;apos;re now running Drupal on Koding! Have fun!
This has been a beginner guide from Koding. As always, more Quick Tips and beginner friendly guides coming soon, so stay tuned!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Markdown Basics, for Koding</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/markdown</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-05-30T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/markdown</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Markdown is a simple language whose syntax can be easily converted into HTML.Koding, like many other sites, use Markdown as a way for users to easily style 
their text. In this guide, we&amp;apos;ll go over the basics of Markdown and it&amp;apos;s usage.
  Official Documentation The official Markdown 
documentation covers the 
Markdown syntax quite well, and as such this guide will only briefly touch on 
each major syntax structure. If any questions remain, please refer to the 
official documentation.
  Emphasis Emphasis can be achieved by wrapping the word you&amp;apos;d like to emphasise with a 
single asterisk or underline. Example:
Hello, *this is emphasised* and this isn&amp;apos;t!

  Strengthen To strengthen your text wrap it with double asterisks or underlines. Example:
Hello, **this is strong** and this isn&amp;apos;t!

  Inline Code Typing code within a sentence is considered inline code. Inline code is 
accomplished by wrapping the code with backticks \ For example:
Foo `bar` baz

  Code Blocks Codeblocks can be achieved by wrapping your code in triple backticks, but make 
sure to include a newline after each tripple backtick. Example:
Take a look at my awesome code:

```coffee
do -&amp;gt; console.log &amp;apos;Weee&amp;apos; while true
```

Nifty eh?
Note the coffee text right behind the first triple backtick. This signifies 
the language of the code used in that code block, and Koding will add syntax 
highlighting if you specify the language.
  Headers # This is a Header 1

## This is a Header 2

The # foo syntax represents headers of varying levels. The number of hashes 
represents the level of header, with a maximum of 6.
  Links [Koding](https://koding.com)
[Koding Terminal, from Koding](/Terminal)

The [foo](bar) syntax will create a link. Links can be absolute or relative, 
just like html links.
  Unordered Lists Unordered lists can be by prepending your items with a hyphen. Example:
- Item one
- Item two
- Item three

Markdown will also embed lists and list content, if you add indentation.Example:
- Item one
- Item two
  This is still within item two.
  - This is a list item in item two.
  - And another
- Item three

  Ordered Lists Ordered lists are identical to unordered lists in features, you just have to 
prepend your list items with a number, instead of a hyphen. Example:
1. Item one
2. Item two
3. Item three

  Images You can easily include images in your markdown by using the following notation:
![Alt text](full url to the image)
![Alt text](full url to the image &amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;)

</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Installing Phalcon on Koding</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-phalcon</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-06-27T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/installing-phalcon</guid>
    <author>Jay</author>
    <description>This article will cover the process of installing and setting up Phalcon in your Koding environment.
  What is Phalcon Phalcon is an open source framework for PHP 5. It differs from other frameworks like Codeigniter, Laravel, etc. in that it is implemented as a C extension. This minimizes memory usage and offers significant performance advantages in comparison to other frameworks.
  Step 1 - Install the Prerequisites Before we can install Phalcon, we need to install the following dependencies:

PHP 5.x development resources
GCC compiler

Open your Koding Terminal and type the following:
sudo apt-get install php5-dev php5-mysql gcc libpcre3-dev
After typing this and hitting enter, you might be prompted for a password. Type in the password of your Koding account and hit enter.
This command might take a few minutes to execute and will fetch and install all the required prerequisites.
  Step 2 - Fetch the Source Code In your Koding Terminal and type the following:
git clone --depth=1 git://github.com/phalcon/cphalcon.git
Executing this command will create a directory named cphalcon and save the latest stable source code in it. We will use this source code to install Phalcon in the next step.
  Step 3 - Install Phalcon Once you have fetched the source code in step 2, type the following two commands in your Koding Terminal:
cd cphalcon/build
sudo ./install
Executing these commands will install the Phalcon extension for PHP in your Koding environment.
  Step 4 - Modify php.ini We now have to modify the php.ini file to include the newly installed Phalcon extension. We can do this by creating a new configuration file for this extension (located at /etc/php5/apache2/conf.d/30-phalcon.ini) and adding the following line to it:
extension=phalcon.so
If you are familiar with vim or nano, you can use either to do this. Alternatively, you can type the following command to append the above line in php.ini:
sudo sh -c &amp;quot;echo &amp;apos;extension=phalcon.so&amp;apos; &amp;gt; /etc/php5/apache2/conf.d/30-phalcon.ini&amp;quot;
This will create the new configuration file and add the required line.
  Step 5 - Restart Apache After completing all the above steps, all that is left to do is restart Apache so that it can load the Phalcon module for PHP. Type in the following command in your Koding Terminal:
sudo service apache2 restart
  Step 6 - Verify the Installation Create a new php file in your public web directory /home/USERNAME/Web (replace USERNAME with your Koding username). You can name it anything but for this example, we&amp;apos;ll name it phpinfo.php. Put the following content in this file:
&amp;lt;?php
phpinfo();
Once this is done, you can open this file in your browser by visiting
http://hostname.username.koding.io/phpinfo.php 
This page should show you the PHP configuration on your machine. 
One of the section contains information about Phalcon (search on the page for phalcon by pressing Ctrl + F). 
If you can see this section, it means that Phalcon has been installed on your machine and you can start using it right away!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Octopress Installation for Beginners</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/octopress-for-beginners</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-04-13T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/octopress-for-beginners</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this article we&amp;apos;ll go over the basics of setting up Octopress.
  What is Octopress? Octopress is a framework built on top of Jekyll, a static site generator. Think of it like easier, friendlier, more powerful Jekyll.
Static site generators get a fair amount of buzz these days, for good reason. They&amp;apos;re simple to maintain, easy to contribute to, and store content in a user friendly manner. The compilation process can sometimes be complex, but at the end of the day your content is understandable by all, and your site has no dependencies to run. No databases to manage, no real points of failure, it&amp;apos;s static.
  Octopress and Koding The only downside to static site generators is publishing the content often requires a local machine of some sort. Non-static sites have the ability to take your input from the browser and save it somewhere such as your Disk or a Database. This complexity allows you to do all of this from your browser, and static sites suffer in this regard.
With Koding this is not the issue. Koding enables the &amp;quot;local machine&amp;quot; entirely in your browser. No local tools needed, no local installs needed, no localhost hassle. Lets go over the process of installing Octopress, on Koding!
  Tutorial Steps 1.) First, we want to get ahold of the Octopress code base. Open your Terminal and run the following two commands to clone Octopress, and navigate into the directory.
git clone git://github.com/imathis/octopress.git octopress 
cd octopress
2.) Next, we need to install some dependencies for Octopress. Run the following commands, which will install Bundle, then use Bundle to install the Octopress dependencies. Lastly, we use rake to set up some directories and initialize our project.
sudo gem install bundle
bundle install
rake install
3.) That&amp;apos;s it for Octopress! But how do we view it? To view it, we need to compile the html and expose that to Apache (our web server). To do this, run the following commands which will generate the html, then symlink our compiled directory as our main Web directory.
rake generate 
mv ~/Web ~/Web.bkp 
ln -s ~/octopress/public ~/Web
4.) Now open up http://hostname.username.koding.io and view your hard 
work!
  All in the browser As always, with Koding, this process was entirely in the browser. No localhost modifications needed, and no worries about installing something incorrectly and mucking up your OS. There is no localhost hassle with Koding!
This has been a getting started tutorial from Koding, with more coming soon. Stay tuned!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Using PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/postgresql-on-koding</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-04-07T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/postgresql-on-koding</guid>
    <author>Federico Ponzi</author>
    <description>PostgreSQL is an open source relational database management system that 
provides an implementation of the SQL query language. In this guide, 
we&amp;apos;ll go over using PostgreSQL on your Koding VM. Lets get started!
  Starting PostgreSQL Before we gets started, start your PostgreSQL server with the following 
command.
sudo service postgresql start
If you see an error like the following message, you may need to go 
through the Installing PostgreSQL.
psql: could not connect to server: No such file or directory
Is the server running locally and accepting
connections on Unix domain socket &amp;quot;/var/run/postgresql/.s.PGSQL.5432&amp;quot;?
  Getting Started To getting started with postgreSQL, open your Terminal, and type:
username$ sudo su - postgres
Now you are logged into your vm with the postgres user. Then connect to template1 database using the postgresql&amp;apos;s psql client:
postgres ~$  psql template1
postgres ~$  template1=#
Note the # symbol, declaring that you are logged to the database as a Super User. Now for enchaned security change your default postgres&amp;apos;s password:
template1=# \password
Enter new password:
Enter it again:
Nice, we are near the end: now create a new user with createdb permission with same username of your vm. So if your username is koding02, your prompt should be like:
koding02 ~$
Create a new user using the CREATE USER command like this:
template1=# CREATE USER username
template1-# WITH PASSWORD &amp;apos;password&amp;apos; createdb;
CREATE ROLE
template1=#
You are done configurating PostgreSQL! Now disconnect from the database using \q, and quit from postgres user using ctrl+d.
Now you can create a new database using the command:
createdb myFreshNewDb
And delete it using the deletedb tool:
deletedb myFreshNewDb
Once you have created a database, you can connect to it using the psql client like we did before:
psql myFreshNewDb
myFresNewDb=&amp;gt;
  Using Psql client Let&amp;apos;s see some useful commands of the psql tool. 
First of all: you can get some help just typing \? in your psql command line.
To exit from the appearing screen, just press the q button.
To load and execute SQL statemens from file, you can use this syntax:
\i my/file/path.sql
Writing long lines of SQL code in the command line can be really hard to debug. Use the \i to run from file or use:
\e
To edit the input buffer with an editor. If you usually don&amp;apos;t use editor from command line use nano - it&amp;apos;s the simplest.
To check what relations your database contains, use
\d
If you want more information about a particular relation, use
\d myfancytable
Have fun!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>PrestaShop Installation for Beginners</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/prestashop-installation-for-beginners</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-04-09T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/prestashop-installation-for-beginners</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this article we&amp;#x2019;ll go over the basics of setting up PrestaShop.
  About PrestaShop A lot of retail stores these days are turning to online shops. It gives them a different power over the products they are selling and in the era of smart gadgets, consumers can now buy almost anything online.
There are a lot of e-commerce solutions, but a there is one that stands out, PrestaShop. You may have heard of it, because it&amp;apos;s all over the news. It&amp;apos;s one of the most reliable and flexible Open-source e-commerce software out there and with a team of 70 developers and with a community that has more than 500.000 members, it sure is a platform worth developing for.
Luckily you can do that on Koding with ease. So how do you setup a PrestaShop shop on Koding? You just follow the next few simple steps and you&amp;apos;re good to go.
  Setting up PrestaShop   Step 1. Open up a Terminal window in Koding and type the following commands to get you started. We navigate to our Web folder and then we try to get the latest version of PrestaShop available on their website. In this case PrestaShop 1.6.0.9 
cd Web; 
wget http://www.prestashop.com/download/prestashop_1.6.0.9.zip;
  Step 2. We unzip the file. 
unzip prestashop_1.6.0.9.zip
  Step 3. We can now head over to the setup page and begin the installation 
procedure. Our link is: 
http://[your_vm_hostname].[your_Koding_username].koding.io/prestashop
All we have to do now is to fill in the required fields to set up the 
shop.
And that&amp;apos;s it, three simple steps to set up your e-commerce solution. As always, more Quick Tips and beginner friendly guides from Koding coming soon, so stay tuned!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting started with Git</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/git</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-06-14T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/git</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Git has become an integral part of the modern software development cycle. As per Wikipedia, Git
&amp;quot;is a distributed revision control and source code management (SCM) system with an emphasis on speed. Git was initially designed and developed by Linus Torvalds for Linux kernel development in 2005.&amp;quot;
Several tutorials exist on the Internet that teach you the basics of Git. A simple Google search will reveal many of them. Here&amp;apos;s our favorite from the good folks over at Atlassian.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>PyroCMS Setup and Installation for Beginners</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/pyrocms-installation-for-beginners</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-03-09T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/pyrocms-installation-for-beginners</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This article will cover the basic steps on how to setup a blog using PyroCMS as the base.
  What&amp;apos;s PyroCMS? Good question. It&amp;apos;s a really simple, flexible and community driven CMS built with the CodeIgniter PHP framework that has an on-growing community of developers and supporters around it.
But how do you set up PyroCMS on Koding? Well it&amp;apos;s simple, you just follow the simple tutorial below step by step. After you&amp;apos;ve finished with the tutorial you&amp;apos;ll have a brand new website that runs PyroCMS.
  Step-by-step PyroCMS   Step 1. Open up your Koding Terminal and type in the following command to get you started. [code]cd Web;[/code]
  Step 2. Still in the terminal window download the source code like so: [code]wget https://www.pyrocms.com/downloads/v2.2.3[/code] or whatever the latest version you can find on the official website.
  Step 3. We rename the downloaded file, unzip it and rename the newly created folder. [code] mv v2.2.3 v2.2.3.zip; unzip v2.2.3.zip; mv pyrocms-pyrocms-08759da pyrocms [/code]
  Step 4. We now can navigate to our newly created folder. We open up a new browser 
window and type in 
[code]http://[your-vm-hostname].[your-Koding-username].koding.io/pyrocms[/code] 
then just follow the steps that show up on the screen to install it.
Alright then, that was fun. You now have a brand new website that runs PyroCMS.
This has been a beginner guide from Koding. As always, more Quick Tips and beginner friendly guides coming soon, so stay tuned!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Setting up a framework webserver</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/setting-framework-webserver</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-06-25T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/setting-framework-webserver</guid>
    <author>Levent Yalcin</author>
    <description>Koding is the easiest way to say goodbye to your localhost. 
Using your personal machine for projects means you have to bind your daemons to public IP address, which can be a bit frustrating for a beginner. Developers usually tend to use certain frameworks that have built-in web servers. These web servers give you the ability to develop your projects and then test them. But there is a downside to that approach. Those web servers are not designated for production usage and besides that they only run locally which makes your daemon/project not accessible to the rest of the world. This means you can&amp;apos;t reach them from your Koding public domain. If you want to achieve this and make you daemons available for public access you have to bind your daemons to 0.0.0.0 which listens to all IPv4 addresses. 
Here are a couple of examples on how to make your project available publicly by using Koding as your development playground.
  Django First we install Django and then create a project.
sudo pip install django
After Django has finished installing we start a new project like so:
django-admin.py startproject goodbyelocalhost
After that we run our built-in web server without binding it to localhost
cd goodbyelocalhost/
python manage.py runserver 0.0.0.0:8000
Voil&amp;#xE0;! You should see a working Django server.
  Laravel 4 and Artisan Installing Laravel 4
sudo curl -o /usr/local/bin/laravel &amp;apos;http://laravel.com/laravel.phar&amp;apos;
Set execute permission on the Laravel executeable.
sudo chmod +x /usr/local/bin/laravel
We create a new new Laravel project.
laravel new goodbyelocalhost
Navigate into the directory:
cd goodbyelocalhost
And then we start the webserver:
php artisan serve --host=0.0.0.0 --port=8080
Voil&amp;#xE0;! A working Laravel and Artisan webserver.
  MeteorJS Before you continue reading this guide why not try a more easy way, using the Koding Package Manager (kpm) and install MeteorJS using just one command:
kpm install meteor

Install MeteorJS
curl https://install.meteor.com/ | sh
Creating a Meteor project is as simple as 1, 2, 3
meteor create goodbyelocalhost
Running the project 
meteor
Meteor should listen to 0.0.0.0:3000 by default. If you can&amp;apos;t reach your project via the browser you have to make sure it listens to 0.0.0.0:3000. You can check this using the netstat command in another terminal window. 
sudo netstat -tnlp
  Rails Rails listens to 0.0.0.0:3000 by default. 
Install Rails via the following command
sudo gem install rails
Create a new project
rails new goodbyetolocalhost
cd goodbyetolocalhost
Start the webserver
rails server
Voil&amp;#xE0;! You have a Rails working webserver
  Tornado Create a new Python script using your favorite editor.
vim goodbyetolocalhost.py
Create a Hello, World! like so, to test if the webserver is running correctly.
import tornado.ioloop
import tornado.web

class MainHandler(tornado.web.RequestHandler):
    def get(self):
        self.write(&amp;quot;Hello, world&amp;quot;)

application = tornado.web.Application([
    (r&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;, MainHandler),
])

if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;:
    application.listen(8888, &amp;apos;0.0.0.0&amp;apos;) 
    tornado.ioloop.IOLoop.instance().start()

Then just run the script
python goodbyetolocalhost.py
  Symphony2 Installing Symphony2
First we need to install composer. Run the following commands to download, move and give right permissions to composer.
curl -sS https://getcomposer.org/installer | php #!/usr/bin/env php
sudo mv composer.phar /usr/local/bin/composer
chmod +x /usr/local/bin/composer
Create a new project to test you webserver.
composer create-project symfony/framework-standard-edition goodbyetolocalhost 
cd goodbyetolocalhost
Start the server like so.
php app/console server:run 0.0.0.0:8080
Enjoy a fully working Symphony2 webserver!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Sync files using Google Drive</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/sync-files-google-drive</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-08T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/sync-files-google-drive</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This guide will cover how to get started with syncronizing your files that are hosted on your Google Drive account (works
with both personal and business Google Apps accounts).
You can install Google Drive on your Koding VM by following these simple steps in Terminal.
  Steps To achieve the sync, we will use an app called grive so first you need to install the grive app using the following command:
sudo apt-get install grive
After that you need to create a folder where the Google Drive folders and files will be synced.
mkdir GDrive
cd GDrive
We need to softlink some dependencies for the grive app to work properly. Use the following command to achieve this.
sudo ln -s /usr/lib/libbfd-2.23.2-system.so /usr/lib/libbfd-2.23-system.so
The last step is to start the Google Drive app and authorize it with the Google services.
grive -a
Cut and paste the link that the grive app shows you into a new browser tab/window to get an authorization code. 
Once you have an auth code, paste it back in the Terminal window to continue the installation process.
Now you can sync you files using the command grive in the GDrive folder you created.
Note 1: The app does not run in the background automatically continuously doing a sync. In order to achieve that, you can
set up a cron job on your VM that runs every x seconds/minutes/hours depending on your preference. To learn
more about cron, open up a new Terminal tab and type in:
man cron
 Note 2: As per the author of grive, the application will not download any files that are the traditional Google Docs (Spreadsheet, Documents,
Presentations, etc.). The app will only automatically upload/download any non-native Google Doc formats which include
code files, text files, images, etc.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>TogetherJS Setup and Usage for Beginners</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/togetherjs-setup-for-beginners</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-03-05T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/togetherjs-setup-for-beginners</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this article we will go over beginner steps for TogetherJS.
  What is TogetherJS? TogetherJS is a drop-in collaboration framework. Think of it like easily adding Google Docs to any site. Normally when you program a real time site, you use a framework like SocketIO, SockJS, or Firebase, and it takes a considerable amount of work just to make content sync up between clients. Adding text chat/mouse tracking/voice chat is a lot of additional work that is often outside the scope of your project. TogetherJS takes away that problem. You focus on your application, and TogetherJS can focus on the difficulty of mouse tracking. With just two lines of code, you get all of these features. Easy! 
  Setting up TogetherJS In the following example, we&amp;apos;ll setup TogetherJS by using a plain html page and the TogetherJS Scripts. 
And just like that, we have a static page with text chat, voice chat, and mouse tracking built into our html page! And because we used Koding we can share this project with our friends easily. On localhost you would have to run a web server, expose and forward your ports, figure out your ip, and finally share it with a friend. Koding saves you that localhost-hassle, and makes this a one-step process. Just share your domain and you&amp;apos;re done. 
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Updating Node.js on your VM</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/updating-nodejs-on-your-vm</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-06-27T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/updating-nodejs-on-your-vm</guid>
    <author>Darryl Dias</author>
    <description>Your Koding VM is powered by Ubuntu 14.04; by default your Koding VM comes pre-installed with Node 0.10.26, the current stable version of Node.js available in the official Ubuntu repository. We can update to the latest stable version of Node.js available for Ubuntu 14.04 by adding the official Node.js PPA to our local sources list and running a dist-upgrade to switch to the latest stable version.
The Official PPA is updated regularly and is maintained by Chris Lea
  Instructions Adding the official Node.js PPA
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:chris-lea/node.js

Updating the local package database and sources list.
sudo apt-get update

Updating to the latest stable build of Node.js available for Ubuntu 14.04. This will update all the packages that need to update and will also update your Node.js package.
sudo apt-get dist-upgrade

If you had deleted Node.js from your VM, you can install it by entering the command below. The PPA installs NPM as a part of nodejs and does not require you to install NPM seperately.
sudo apt-get install nodejs

Check the version of Node.js after installing. 
node --version

The example output should look like.
v0.10.33

Now you have the latest stable version of Node.js installed on your VM.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Using Tmux on Koding</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/using-tmux-on-koding</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-05-13T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/using-tmux-on-koding</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this Tmux FAQ we will address an issue people have had with Tmux on Koding. It&amp;apos;s easy to deal with, but not an obvious workaround.
  Odd Behavior When you first try and install and run tmux on Koding, it seems to load properly, but many commands just don&amp;apos;t seem to work. Some, like C-b c (used to create a new window) even force close the Terminal. What is going on?
Well, Koding uses GNU Screen to help reconnect your Terminal sessions after connection issues. Koding&amp;apos;s preconfigured Screen is set to use C-b as it&amp;apos;s own prefix key. So when you run and use Tmux, and attempt to use C-b commands, you are actually sending commands to Screen. This explains the general odd behavior, as things like C-b c in Screen mean &amp;quot;close&amp;quot;, so you unintentionally logout of screen and close your Terminal.
  The Solution The solution is quite simple, rebind your Tmux Prefix key. This can be done by creating a ~/.tmux.conf file and placing the following command into it:
set-option -g prefix C-a
Where C-a is Control key. This sets it to Control-a, a popular alternative for Tmux users (and the traditional Screen PREFIX). You can of course bind it to whatever you want. Once you have your PREFIX rebound, killall tmux instances and reopen, and it will run just like you expect.. just remember to use Control-a as your PREFIX :)
  But i love C-b! Unfortunately, this is the way it has to be for now. A guru developer over at Koding did mention that they would like to make their version of screen not use any keybinds, so that it does not block your input at all. So, think of this alternate bind as a short-term workaround, until this &amp;quot;issue&amp;quot; is resolved.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>What is Koding?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/what-is-koding</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-02-17T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/what-is-koding</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Koding is an online cloud-based development environment with the goal of 
simplifying worldwide development and providing free computation and 
development to everyone. It does this by offering Free VMs for development 
to anyone. The Koding VMs provide you with a real Ubuntu OS, with a real 
Terminal, and allow you to work on real code. It can be any language, be 
it Python, PHP, C++, C, or anything else, it doesn&amp;apos;t matter. Even better, 
the VMs are hosted on the cloud, so they&amp;apos;re accessible from just about anywhere 
in the world.
  Is Koding a Production Host? Koding is first and foremost a Development Environment, and not a Production 
Host. All features have been tailored with this in mind and evidence of this is 
reflected in all of the features you see implemented. Lets highlight some of 
these items.
  VMs Shutdown After Logout Approximately 60 minutes after you log out, your Free VMs will shut down. Why? 
Koding&amp;apos;s development focus is not centered around hosting your blog/site. 
Koding is here to enable you and to help you make great things. Attempting to 
be yet another host in a sea of perfectly capable production hosts won&amp;apos;t help 
achieve that goal.
Another benefit of this system, is that it helps avoid security concerns that 
collectively harm us all. There are plenty of users out there who have used 
Koding to host dangerous applications. Phishing, scamming, spamming, all of it. 
This directly harms all of us, by giving Koding a bad name, wasting resources, 
and hindering a service that we are trying to be productive with. It&amp;apos;s no 
surprise that restrictions need to be put in place to inhibit this behavior, 
for the benefit of everyone.
However, if you upgrade your plan, you will have at least one Always-On VM. The 
number of Always-On VMs you have depends on which plan you upgrade to. More 
information about these plans can be found here. 
You can upgrade your plan from the Pricing page. 
Always-On VMs will never shut down automatically.
  CPU Bursts vs Sustained Koding wants to help you get work done, and get work done fast. Things like 
compilers have a lot to compute, but in short sporadic bursts. 
Koding&amp;apos;s CPU allocation has been tailored with this in mind. It wants you to 
compute what you need, as soon as possible. It is not designed for a long 
running process that expects heavy and consistent usage, such as a 
Minecraft server.
  Raw Ubuntu OS These days a lot of hosting platforms are heavily optimized for their specific 
niche(s). They streamline the process of hosting your language or application 
style of choice, which gives you added stability and performance gains. 
Examples of this are the plethora of Apache-PHP hosts, Nodejitsu, Google App 
Engine, Heroku, AppFog, and a nearly limitless amount of others.
Why is this? Well, production hosting is hard, and there are obvious benefits 
to letting someone else do it. The idea of uploading your php site to a 
standard php host is easy. The idea of buying a dedicated server, setting up 
Apache, firewalls, updates, etc, just seems a bit crazy in comparison. On top 
of that, what about load balancing and CDNs? Doing it all yourself can be hard.
Well, Koding gives you that raw machine. It&amp;apos;s not trying to make production 
hosting for you, but rather it&amp;apos;s giving you a completely open and powerful 
environment to make stuff! So by all means make your Wordpress blog on 
Koding, and if you really want to host it on Koding, upgrade your plan to 
include an Always-On VM. Just be aware of the design goals.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Setting up WebDav on Koding</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/setting-up-webdav-on-koding</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-03-16T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/setting-up-webdav-on-koding</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This tutorial will cover the basics on how to set up WebDav on Koding and then connect to it using a Mac, Windows or Ubuntu machine. We already know how to set up FTP and SSH, but what about WebDav? Just follow the steps below. 
  Steps The first step is to open up the Terminal app and type the following commands. 
sudo a2enmod dav
sudo a2enmod dav_fs
sudo nano /etc/apache2/sites-enabled/000-default
When the file opens from the last command, we just paste in this configuration and save it. 
Alias /webdav1 /var/www/WebDAV1
&amp;lt;Directory /var/www/WebDAV1/&amp;gt;
 Options Indexes MultiViews
 AllowOverride None
 Order allow,deny
 allow from all
 &amp;lt;/Directory&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;Location /webdav1&amp;gt;
 DAV On
 AuthType Basic
 AuthName &amp;quot;webdav1&amp;quot;
 AuthUserFile /etc/apache2/webdav.password
 Require valid-user
&amp;lt;/Location&amp;gt;
The third step is to create the folder that will be used to store the files. You can do this by entering these commands: 
cd ~/Web
mkdir WebDAV1
chown -R www-data.www-data WebDAV1
The last step is to set up a password, of your choosing, and after that to restart the Apache server. You can do this by entering the commands below, where is your Koding username. 
sudo htpasswd -c /etc/apache2/webdav.password &amp;lt;USERNAME&amp;gt;
sudo service apache2 reload
Just remember to restart the Apache server so that all the settings that 
we made so far are remembered, and you&amp;apos;re good to go. Now, what about 
connecting to it? Sure. It&amp;apos;s super simple stuff. We can check if our 
WebDAV works by heading over to 
http://..koding.io/webdav1 and then when the box 
pops up we just enter our username and the password we set up earlier.For local connection you can follow these steps. 
  On Mac OS The Apple support website offers the quickest solution to our problem. Just follow the guide located here. 
  On Windows OS On a Windows machine we need NetDrive. You can download it by clicking this 
link. After we install 
and open it, we need to add a New Site.  The 
settings are as followed: 

Site Name: Koding
Site IP or URL: http://..koding.io/webdav1
Server Type: WebDav
Drive: 
Account: 
Password: 
We then hit connect and it should work. 

  On Ubuntu On Ubuntu we can quickly test and use our newly created WebDav by using just the command line. First we need to install cadaver. Cadaver is a command line WebDav client. 
sudo apt-get install cadaver
After that we connect to our WebDav like this 
cadaver http://&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.koding.io/webdav1/
After the connection is established we enter our username and password and we&amp;apos;re good to go. 
cadaver http://&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.koding.io/webdav1
Authentication required for test on server 
`http://&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.koding.io/webdav1`:
Username: &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;
Password: *******
dav:/webdav1/&amp;gt; quit
Connection to `http://&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.koding.io/webdav1` 
closed.
That is all. If you have any issues setting up WebDav you can drop an email at support@koding.com
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started: The UI</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/the-ui</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-05-30T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/the-ui</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll take a look at Koding&amp;apos;s UI. We&amp;apos;ll examine 
the major sections, and briefly explain some of the features. In future 
guides of this series we&amp;apos;ll explain these parts in more detail. Lets get 
started!
  The Full UI 
This is the Koding UI of a logged in user, with the Koding IDE 
open. On the left side we have our VMs, Channels, Chats, and Account. To 
the right we have the Koding IDE. Lets look at each piece, and where they 
lead us.
  VMs, Workspaces and IDE VMs, Workspaces, and the Koding IDE can be found on the left hand 
side, under VMS, as seen in the image below.

Clicking on a VM Name, such as koding-vm-0 in the above image, will 
open up the Koding IDE for that specific VM.
The button to the immediate right of the VM Name is the VM Settings. Here 
you can find useful information, such as your VM Address and VM Specs.
Finally, below the VM Name are your Workspaces for that specific VM.Clicking on a Workspace will open all of the previous editors and 
Terminals that you had open on it, and opening new Workspaces provides 
shortcuts for varying tasks. We&amp;apos;ll get into the specifics in the 
Workspaces guide.
  Channels and Activity Below VMs, are your Channels. To follow a channel, click on a Grey check 
mark. Green check marks indicate a channel that you are following.

A channel is a stream of user submitted content for a certain hash tag, 
such as #golang. When you 
click on a hash tag in the Activity Feed, it opens a channel for that 
tag, as seen below.

Activity Feed posts support Markdown, including Markdown Code 
Blocks.
  Chat Below Channels are your Chats. These are private conversations between 
you and any number of users you invite.

To open a new chat, click on the Plus button to the right of the Chat 
icon. Clicking on a already started chat, will open it as seen below.

Your chats will work much in the same way as the Activity Feed. You can 
invite more users by clicking the Plus next to user icons, or delete the 
conversation from the Chat Dropdown in the upper right.
  Account Settings Your Account Settings can be located from the bottom of the navigation 
panel.

Here you&amp;apos;ll be able to modify your Name, Password, and link your Koding 
account to various services.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>General .htaccess</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/general-htaccess</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-02-02T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/general-htaccess</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Htaccess is a pretty well understood and standard feature among web hosts. Koding&amp;apos;s .htaccess is no different than any other, so the plethora of tutorials and information out there will work perfectly fine on Koding.
  RewriteEngine &amp;amp; mod_rewrite For the sake of discussion, lets say I have two Koding domains 
http://username.koding.io and http://my.name.is.username.koding.io.How would I forward the first to the second?
Htaccess makes this pretty simple. Create a .htaccess file in your Web directory, if you don&amp;apos;t already have one, touch ~/Web/.htaccess &amp;amp;&amp;amp; chmod 644 ~/Web/.htaccess and add the following RewriteRule:
RewriteEngine On RewriteCond %{HTTP_HOST} ^username.koding.io [NC] 
RewriteRule ^(.*) http://my.name.is.username.koding.io/$1 [R=301]
But wait, if we go to http://username.koding.io now we are presented 
with the following error:
`\ Internal Server Error
The server encountered an internal error or misconfiguration and was unable to complete your request.
Please contact the server administrator, webmaster@localhost and inform them of the time the error occurred, and anything you might have done that may have caused the error.
More information about this error may be available in the server error log. `\
The reason for this is that mod_rewrite is not enabled by default. The fix for this is insanely easy, run the following command:
sudo a2enmod rewrite &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo service apache2 restart
This uses the command a2enmod to enable mod_rewrite, and then restarts 
apache. Now if we go to http://username.koding.io we are redirected to 
http://my.name.is.username.koding.io. Yay!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Enable PHP mail() function</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/enable-php-mail-function</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-12T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/enable-php-mail-function</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This short guide will cover how to enable the mail() function in PHP.
The first thing you need to do is install the sendmail package. Do this by running the following command in your Koding Terminal:
sudo apt-get install sendmail
After the previous command finishes installing the sendmail package, you need to configure it. You can do that by running the following command, which will configure the mail server:
sudo sendmailconfig
You need to choose Yes to every question or otherwise configure it as you see fit.
That&amp;apos;s it! You can now use the mail() function in your PHP app. 
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>EmberJS: A Starting Kit for Beginners</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/emberjs-starting-kit</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-03-02T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/emberjs-starting-kit</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Ambitious applications are the future. The way we interact with a web application will impact our productivity. That&amp;apos;s why in this short tutorial we are going to cover some of the basics of EmberJS.
  EmberJS: The facts They say that if you use EmberJS you don&amp;apos;t have to reinvent the wheel. Well we say that they are right. EmberJS is built for developers by developers. It&amp;apos;s friendly, fast and definitely a good alternative if you want to build something awesome. And we here at Koding like it when people build awesome stuff, therefor this tutorial is here to help you get started with one of the most on-growing and well-built frameworks out there. Right, now let&amp;apos;s get started on how to set up EmberJS on Koding. 
  The Steps   Step 1. We open up a new file using your favorite code editor inside Koding, because as you may know, you have Ace pre-installed or maybe you&amp;apos;re a Vim or Emacs individual. For the sake of this tutorial we are going to use the Ace editor. 
  Step 2. We copy and paste the following code into are newly created file.
&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta charset=utf-8 /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Ember Koding 
Demo&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/x-handlebars&amp;quot; 
data-template-name=&amp;quot;index&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Ember.js on Koding&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; {{#each item 
in model}} &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;{{item}}&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; {{/each}} &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script 
src=&amp;quot;//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/jquery/2.0.3/jquery.min.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; 
&amp;lt;script 
src=&amp;quot;//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/handlebars.js/1.1.2/handlebars.min.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; 
&amp;lt;script 
src=&amp;quot;//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/ember.js/1.1.2/ember.min.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; 
&amp;lt;script&amp;gt; App = Ember.Application.create({}); App.IndexRoute = 
Ember.Route.extend({ setupController: function(controller) { 
controller.set(&amp;apos;content&amp;apos;, [&amp;apos;cyan&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;magenta&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;penguin&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;pie&amp;apos;]); } }); 
&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
 Ok now that we saved the file and opened up the preview and saw that 
everything worked as it should let&amp;apos;s explain a bit what is actually 
happening. First, before everything, we need the following libraries that 
make our EmberJS app work: jQuery, handlebars and of course emberJS. The 
app uses handlebars for templating.  After we set up the template and 
loaded the libraries we need to create the actual app. First we 
initialize ember and then we use a Router that helps to manage the state 
of the application and the resources needed as a user navigates the app.In our case set some content using the already created template that was 
made possible with the help of the handlebars library. And there you have 
it. A short tutorial on how to use EmberJS on 
Koding.
As always, more Quick Tips and beginner friendly guides 
from Koding coming soon, so stay tuned!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Elixir on Koding</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/elixir-on-koding</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-09T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/elixir-on-koding</guid>
    <author>Antoine Proulx</author>
    <description>This tutorial will show you how to install Elixir on your Koding VM and then how to update it when a new version is available.
  What is Elixir? From Elixir website:

Elixir is a functional, meta-programming aware language built on top of the Erlang VM. It is a dynamic language that focuses on tooling to leverage Erlang&amp;apos;s abilities to build concurrent, distributed and fault-tolerant applications with hot code upgrades.

  Installation Because Elixir runs on the Erlang VM, you need to install Erlang first. At the time of this 
writing, Elixir is at version 0.14.2 and it needs at least Erlang 17.
  Erlang To install Erlang, you can use the Erlang Solutions repository.
The first thing to do is to add the repository. To do that, open the Terminal and then enter the following:
wget http://packages.erlang-solutions.com/erlang-solutions_1.0_all.deb
sudo dpkg -i erlang-solutions_1.0_all.deb

The wget command will download a package that will be used to add the 
Erlang Solutions repository and the other one installs it.
You can now install Erlang by typing this in the Terminal:
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install erlang

(When prompted if you want to continue, type y and then Enter.)
This will refresh the list of available packages and then install Erlang.
  Elixir Now that you have Erlang, you can install Elixir. To do this, we&amp;apos;ll use a precompiled version and place it in ~/lang/elixir.
In the following commands, you need to replace [elixir-version] by the value of the latest version that you&amp;apos;ll find on the download page. For example, at the time of this writing, Elixir is at version 0.14.2, so you would replace [elixir-version] with 0.14.2.
mkdir -p ~/lang/elixir
wget -O elixir.zip https://github.com/elixir-lang/elixir/releases/download/v[elixir-version]/Precompiled.zip
unzip elixir.zip -d ~/lang/elixir

The last thing you need to do is to add the Elixir binaries to your PATH. Your terminal will now know where to find Elixir.
First, open up your .profile file using nano:
nano ~/.profile

Then, at the end of the file, add:
PATH=$PATH:~/lang/elixir/bin

To exit nano and save the file, type Ctrl+x, y and then Enter.
To apply the modification to the PATH immediately, type:
source ~/.profile

Elixir is now installed!
  Usage The easiest way to begin with Elixir is to use Interactive Elixir. In your terminal, type iex to start it. You can now enter Elixir expressions and see their results.
The last thing you need to do is to learn Elixir!
  Update When a new version of Erlang and/or Elixir is released, you will want to update your installation.
  Erlang Because Erlang has been installed with apt-get, the only thing you need to do is to run the following command in your Terminal:
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get upgrade

The first command will update the list of the available packages and the second one will download 
and install the packages that have been updated in the repositories.
  Elixir Updating Elixir is not very complicated. First, you need to remove the old installation by issuing the following command in your Terminal:
rm -r ~/lang/elixir

Then, you can download the latest version of Elixir and extract the content of the archive like this (do not forget to replace [elixir-version]!):
mkdir -p ~/lang/elixir
wget -O elixir.zip https://github.com/elixir-lang/elixir/releases/download/v[elixir-version]/Precompiled.zip
unzip elixir.zip -d ~/lang/elixir

Elixir is now updated!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Codeigniter Installation for Beginners</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/codeigniter-for-beginners</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-01-07T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/codeigniter-for-beginners</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this article we will go over installing Codeigniter for beginners.
  What is Codeigniter? Codeigniter may be old hat to some, but the tried and true frameworks tend to hold their own for quite a long time, and for good reason. It is polished, has an extensive history, and above all has a large community to back it up. 
  So how do i get started with Codeigniter? In the following video, we&amp;#x2019;ll go over the basic process of running Codeigniter on Koding. 
As you can see, setting up CI is a pretty simple process. The only 
trouble is ensuring that your LAMP stack is up and running properly, but 
thanks to Koding this process was made easy. Koding 
comes with Apache by default, so Codeigniter just works. On top of 
that, we were able to get started with Codeigniter entirely in our 
browser. No downloading and installing LAMP stacks to our localhost 
required. 
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>What happened to 127.0.0.1?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/what-happened-to-127-0-0-1</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-10T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/what-happened-to-127-0-0-1</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Users who are new to Koding development are often confused about why they are 
not seeing their NodeJS, Python, Ruby or etc Apps on their Koding Domain. This 
guide will explain this common issue, and how to work around it.
  0.0.0.0, your new 127.0.0.1 In short, use 0.0.0.0 for your Web Server IP instead of 127.0.0.1 on 
Koding. Lets dig a little deeper though, and explain what this means, and why.
  Why should i use 0.0.0.0? When you run web server applications they need an IP and Port to listen on.
Many development applications will default the IP to 127.0.0.1, the 
machine&amp;apos;s localhost. This works fine on your Laptop, because you are 
accessing your web server locally. When you use a Koding VM, you typically 
access it from the Koding Domain, which means that you&amp;apos;re accessing your 
web application externally. Meaning that connecting to 
hostname.username.koding.io:3000 will not respond with a web server 
running on 127.0.0.1:3000.
To solve this issue, we turn to our friendly 0.0.0.0 IP. Unlike 127.0.0.1, 
this IP will accept connections from any source. Localhost, or external.
  An example To help illustrate the above explanation, lets run a little NodeJS server and 
use curl and our browser to request it from multiple locations. If you want 
to follow along, copy the following code into a file named hello.js.
require(&amp;apos;http&amp;apos;).createServer(function(req, res) {
  res.end(&amp;apos;Hello!\n&amp;apos;);
}).listen(3000, process.argv[2]);
console.log(&amp;apos;Sending greetings on &amp;apos;, process.argv[2] + &amp;apos;:3000&amp;apos;);

Now that we&amp;apos;ve creating our little Node server, lets open up our 
Terminal and run it with the following.
node hello.js 127.0.0.1
Next, lets visit out domain at the following address, making sure to replace 
username with your Koding username.
http://hostname.username.koding.io:3000
As you can see from the following two images, our web server is not responding 
on our domain but it is responding with curl localhost.


As we previous discussed, we need to bind our NodeJS server to the 0.0.0.0 
address. Lets run our web server again with the proper address.
node hello.js 0.0.0.0
And open it up in our browser just like before.

Success!
Remember that the way in which you choose the IP of your Web Server can differ 
greatly between web frameworks. In this above example, we wrote our own web 
server, which accepts a single argument (the bind ip).
Look at the documentation for your web framework of choice, as it will almost 
certainly be different than what was used in this example.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Where is my Web Server Root?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/where-is-my-webserver-root</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-07-09T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/where-is-my-webserver-root</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>Koding VMs come with Apache preconfigured and serve a sample site to get you 
started. The files for this site are found in what is typically called your 
Web Server Root. This is the directory that Apache is serving up files from, 
and it is located within your Home directory, under the Web directory. The 
full path being:
/home/username/Web
Replace username with your username.
You can modify the contents of this directory with the Koding 
Terminal, or the Ace Editor. In this example, we&amp;apos;ll use Ace 
to browse the files with the FileTree.
First, open up Ace. In the left hand side you&amp;apos;ll see a FileTree, with a 
directory called Web. Double click the Web folder to expand it. Your FileTree 
should look something like this:

Those files are a series of example pages, and they&amp;apos;re being served by Apache 
on your Koding Domain. You can view this site by visiting your Koding Domain, 
at:
http://hostname.username.koding.io
Where username is your Koding username. You should see something like this:

You&amp;apos;ll notice that the PHP, Python, Perl, and Ruby links are actually files 
being generated from that language. As an example, the python.py file is 
being served up by Apache, with the aid of Apache&amp;apos;s mod_python module. This 
serves to illustrate that this is a real Apache server, and you can use it 
just like you expect.
You should now understand where your Web Server Root is, and how to access it 
from the Web to develop and share your web applications. Happy Koding!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>CakePHP Installation for Beginners</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/cakephp-for-beginners</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-04-01T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/cakephp-for-beginners</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this article we will installing CakePHP for beginners.
  What is CakePHP? CakePHP is a popular PHP framework created with ease of use, small codebase, and MVC in mind. It&amp;apos;s also being actively developed, with two point releases in the last month alone. With a solid codebase, a supportive community, and active developers, it is a strong choice for any project. 
  CakePHP and Koding Of course, CakePHP is especially easy on Koding. Developing locally means you need to already have a php framework up and running, as well as a database (MySQL for example). This becomes even more troublesome if you want to share your work with coworkers or friends. Exposing your ports to the outside world, finding your ip, and then sharing it. Thankfully on Koding this is a one step process. You already have the entire LAMP stack available to you, all from your browser. Likewise, sharing with your friends is as easy as sharing your Koding Domain. So, lets use Koding, shall we? 
  Installing CakePHP Steps 1.) On the homepage of CakePHP, copy the download link for the latest 
version of CakePHP. In this case we&amp;apos;re going to be using CakePHP 
2.4.2. 2.) Open your 
Koding Terminal and type in wget 
-O cake.zip and then paste your download link with Ctrl-Shift-V. As an 
example, it should look like this: wget -O cake.zip 
https://github.com/cakephp/cakephp/zipball/2.4.2 3.) On the left hand 
side, in the Koding FileTree, right click your file and choose Extract.This will extract your downloaded Cakezip into the directory cake/.Expand that directory, and you&amp;apos;ll see a directory with a name similar to 
cakephp-cakephp-f53efef. 4.) Drag that into your Web/ directory. You 
can rename this directory to &amp;quot;cake&amp;quot;, or whatever you like, as this will 
make it easier to type in your browser. 5.) Finally lets ensure that we 
have Apache&amp;apos;s mod_rewrite enabled. Run sudo a2enmod rewrite &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo 
service apache2 restart just to be safe. If you already have mod_rewrite 
enabled, you can skip this step. 6.) The last step is a security step 
enforced by CakePHP. Open up app/Config/core.php and look for the 
following two lines. Edit the DYhG93b0qyJfIxfs2guVoUubWwvniR2G0FgaC9mi 
and 76859309657453542496749683645 strings to have randomized content 
for your deploy. Just remember that the second string is numbers only.  
/** * A random string used in security hashing methods. */ 
Configure::write(&amp;apos;Security.salt&amp;apos;, 
&amp;apos;DYhG93b0qyJfIxfs2guVoUubWwvniR2G0FgaC9mi&amp;apos;); /** * A random numeric 
string (digits only) used to encrypt/decrypt strings. */ 
Configure::write(&amp;apos;Security.cipherSeed&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;76859309657453542496749683645&amp;apos;);
7.) That&amp;apos;s it! Now just open up http://hostname.username.koding.io/cake 
in your browser, making sure to use your own username in the username 
url, and you&amp;apos;ll see Cake up and running! 
  All in the browser Thanks to Koding, our only requirement to get cake downloaded and running, in the browser. No special OS installation steps, no need to set up your own LAMP stack, no localhost hassle. This has been a beginner guide for CakePHP from Koding and we have more tutorials and guides on the way soon. Stay tuned!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-02-07T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this Getting Started series, lets go over some basic usage of Koding. We&amp;apos;ll 
go over each section, and by the end you should have a basic understanding how 
where everything is located in Koding. 
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>AngularJS Step-by-Step Setup</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/angularjs-step-by-step</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-03-09T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/angularjs-step-by-step</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>This article is all about AngularJS and how to get you started with it on 
Koding.
  AngularJS: What&amp;apos;s it all about. Everything is dynamic these days, or at least in should be. The age of the static documents is slightly fading away and people like to interact with websites and applications in real-time. Queue frameworks that offer dynamism to web apps. These frameworks offer an endless list of possibilities and give developers free reign over how people interact with their application, in real-time. One of the most popular frameworks these days, that is starting to be approached by more and more developers is AngularJS. AngularJS can be used with any application development workflow due to the fact that it&amp;apos;s extensible and because it works well with other libraries. 
  Setting it up on Koding Ok, but how can we develop a web application in the cloud and preview the 
result a the same time? It&amp;apos;s easy, we use Koding!Koding&amp;apos;s built-in preview system enables you to preview 
your progress with a single click. It&amp;apos;s as simple as 1,2,3. So let&amp;apos;s get 
started then. First we create a new .html file using the Ace editor app, that 
comes pre-installed with Koding, or any editor you prefer 
or have installed. The next step is to head over to the AngularJS 
website and get one of their simple examples. For this 
tutorial we&amp;apos;re going to use the first tutorial that comes up, a simple &amp;quot;Hello!&amp;quot; 
example. We copy that and paste it into our file, the one that we created 
earlier.
&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html ng-app&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;script 
    src=&amp;quot;https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/angularjs/1.2.0/angular.min.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;label&amp;gt;Name:&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;
        ng-model=&amp;quot;yourName&amp;quot;
        placeholder=&amp;quot;Enter a name here&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;hr&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Hello {{yourName}}!&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;

We can now save our file and check out the result, by clicking the little 
&amp;quot;hamburger&amp;quot; menu in the top right corner of Ace editor and then choose Preview.The example we got should display nicely. Go ahead and test to see if it 
works.  Simple and fun!
And that&amp;apos;s it. Why not continue and experiment with AngularJS on 
Koding and see what more cool stuff you can 
make. As always, more Quick Tips and beginner friendly guides coming 
soon, so stay tuned!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Getting Started: The Activity Feed</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/activity-feed</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-05-30T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/getting-started/activity-feed</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>The Activity Feed is the central location for discussion on Koding. A 
public message board, with markdown support, previewing, hashtag topics 
and more, it&amp;apos;s a central component to Koding&amp;apos;s Social experience.

  Posting and Formatting To post to the activity feed, find the input box in the top of the page.

Simply type something in, and press the green submit button. Just plain text 
can get a bit boring though, so Koding supports full 
Markdown, as seen below:

  Previewing To preview your post, simply press the little eye on the right side of 
the input box. Your Markdown will be rendered and highlighted 
appropriately.

  Tagging Tagging your content is important. With tags, your content can be
categorized, which makes it easier to search and more likely to be seen 
by people who follow those channels.



Here you can see the previous Markdown example, tagged with the 
#markdown tag.
  Searching On the #public channel there is a search field next to 
Most Liked / Most Recent, as seen below.

Searching the activity feed will search for the contents of a post, as 
well as the tags.
  Channels Channels are how you view a steam of posts with a certain Tag. When you 
click on a tag, it opens a channel for that tag. Clicking on the Grey 
checkmark next to the channel name, will subscribe you to that channel, 
and keep it open anytime you visit Koding.

To browse channels that you might be interested in, you can click the 
Plus button next to &amp;quot;Channel&amp;quot; in the sidebar (as seen below), and 
search for the channel you&amp;apos;re interested in.

Following channels is a great way to stay active in content that matters 
to you.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Author a guide: Advanced</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/contribute/advanced</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-06-01T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/contribute/advanced</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll go over contributing by using Git directly in your 
Terminal, and editing our documents on Koding. While we will go over 
every step, general Git and Terminal knowledge will be very helpful, and 
are recommended. So, lets get started!
  Forking and Cloning First up, we should cover the requirements.

A Koding Account
A Github Account
Git (Comes with your Koding VM)
SSH Key on Github. If you&amp;apos;re not familiar with this, refer to this 
tutorial

Next, we need to &amp;quot;Fork&amp;quot; the KDLearn Repo. This will create your 
own version of the repo on Github, and lets you push your changes to this 
repo.
To do this, press the Fork button seen in the following image, from the 
KDLearn repo page:

This will create a new Github repository with the name 
github.com/yourUsername/kdlearn. The purpose of this forked repository 
will become clear once we make our Pull Request.
Next, we will want to clone our newly forked repository. Head on over to 
your Koding Terminal and type in the following command:
git clone https://github.com/yourUsername/kdlearn.git
This will clone your Forked Repository to your Koding VM, into the folder 
kdlearn.
  Writing a new Guide Now that we have our repo cloned, lets add our guide. Open up the Ace 
editor and open a folder titled kdlearn. In this section we&amp;apos;re 
going to write a guide, but if you just want to edit another guide, 
scroll down to the edit section.
Lets create a file in the guides folder with the name myguide.md.Name the file whatever you like, just try to keep it short and url 
friendly.

This is where we will write all of our content, in Markdown. For this 
tutorial i am just going to use the following text:
# Awesome Guide

This is my **awesome** guide! Follow along, and learn to be awesome!

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Suspendisse dui 
nulla, posuere non urna in, lobortis malesuada erat. Morbi ultricies 
fringilla condimentum. Aliquam vel sodales mi, ornare ullamcorper est.  
Nulla laoreet dapibus libero, in consectetur dolor fermentum vel. Etiam 
quis magna eget orci fringilla tincidunt et non justo. Phasellus porta 
dictum libero. Suspendisse fringilla gravida arcu, eu venenatis nunc 
fermentum sed. Phasellus est libero, auctor ac dignissim ac, consequat a 
libero. Pellentesque iaculis sem tortor.  Suspendisse viverra, arcu ac 
viverra dapibus, massa odio adipiscing neque, eget adipiscing magna quam 
id dui. Morbi semper nisi ac accumsan tincidunt.

Now that we have written our guide, we need to add some metadata to it.
  Metadata Metadata is, as the name says, data about our data. This is where you can 
specify the title of your document, the author, the date, and categories.Lets take a look at our above markdown with some of this metadata.
---
author: Lee Olayvar
username: leeolayvar
date: 2014-06-11
description: &amp;apos;My awesome guide, about awesome stuff.&amp;apos;
categories: [awesome]
---

# Awesome Guide

This is my **awesome** guide! Follow along, and learn to be awesome!

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Suspendisse dui nulla, 
posuere non urna in, lobortis malesuada erat. Morbi ultricies fringilla 
condimentum. Aliquam vel sodales mi, ornare ullamcorper est. Nulla laoreet 
dapibus libero, in consectetur dolor fermentum vel. Etiam quis magna eget orci 
fringilla tincidunt et non justo. Phasellus porta dictum libero. Suspendisse 
fringilla gravida arcu, eu venenatis nunc fermentum sed. Phasellus est libero, 
auctor ac dignissim ac, consequat a libero. Pellentesque iaculis sem tortor.  
Suspendisse viverra, arcu ac viverra dapibus, massa odio adipiscing neque, eget 
adipiscing magna quam id dui. Morbi semper nisi ac accumsan tincidunt.

Most of that is pretty logical. The --- before and after signifies the 
metadata start and end, and author, date, description, and categories 
should be standard nomenclature to you.
  Editing a Guide If you&amp;apos;re just looking to update a guide, fix typos, or make general 
improvements you have it even easier.
Just like before, open up Ace and find the file you want to edit.If you&amp;apos;re not sure where the proper markdown is located, find the url of 
the page you want to edit and think of them like folders. Then, review 
the File Structre section and you should have a pretty 
good idea where the files are located.
Make your edits, and follow onto the next section!
  Adding, Committing, Pushing Now that we have made our changes, whether it&amp;apos;s a new guide or an edited 
guide, we need to add the file, commit it, and push it to our repo. Open 
up the Terminal one last time.
To add your changes, run the following command. Replacing myguide with 
the files you changed.
git add guides/myguide.md
To commit your changes, run the following command. Replacing I added an 
awesome guide with a message that clearly describes your changes.
git commit -m &amp;quot;I added an awesome guide&amp;quot;
You can also ommit the whole -m &amp;quot;message&amp;quot; flag and use an editor such 
as Nano or Vim to make your changes. But the above is simpler for this 
guide.
And finally, lets push our changes to our repo on Github.
git push origin master
If you&amp;apos;re not familiar with Git at all, run each of these commands in 
sequence.  We won&amp;apos;t be covering Git in full, so for more information 
please see the official documentation.
  Making a Pull Request Now that you pushed to Github you can visit your forked Github repository 
and make a pull request. To do this, look for the &amp;quot;Pull Request&amp;quot; button 
on your forked repo:

This will take you to a page where you can review all of the commits you 
made, and ensure that you want to make a pull request. Please review your 
changes for typos, spelling, and grammar.
If you spot an issue, and need to make more changes, go back to 
Koding and make the edits you need. Make sure to add, commit, and 
push them just like before.
If you&amp;apos;re happy with your changes, press the big green Create Pull 
Request button.
  Waiting for your PR to be Accepted Once your PR is made, you&amp;apos;re done! The Koding Team will review your edits 
or new guides and make feedback.
If we need you to make corrections, formatting or otherwise, go through 
the same steps as before. Your changes, once pushed to Github, will 
automatically be reflected in your Pull Request.
Once they are accepted, and your pull request is merged, the site will be 
updated and you&amp;apos;re changes will be live. Thanks for your contribution!
In the next guide we&amp;apos;ll go over previewing your work in a local 
installation of Koding University.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>How to setup an SSH Tunnel in Unix</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/ssh-tunneling</link>
    <pubDate>2014-08-9</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/ssh-tunneling</guid>
    <author>Team Koding</author>
    <description>In this guide we&amp;apos;ll go over what SSH Tunneling is, what it&amp;apos;s used for, 
and how to set one up on your Koding VM. So, lets get started!
  What is SSH Tunneling? SSH Tunneling is the process of sending and receiving TCP and UDP packets 
through an SSH Connection. This enables you to bypass proxies and go 
directly to your VM, with whatever data/etc that you need.
  Why would I want to SSH Tunnel? Koding Virtual Machines do not have direct IP access. They proxy http 
connections from your domain, to the machine itself. Note that only HTTP 
is proxied. This is why when you SSH into your VM, you set up a special 
SSH config to run your connection through ssh.koding.com.
Because of this Proxy, some things you may want to do on Koding, such as 
connecting a MySQL Database Client directly to your MySQL Server becomes 
impossible via the username domains.
To solve this, you use SSH Tunneling to connect to servers directly on 
your VM, from your local machine. Lets take a look at how this is done.
  Using a SSH Tunnel First up, make sure you have gone through the SSH Guide, and 
can successfully connect to your VM using the steps outlined in that 
guide. You must have a working SSH connection for this to work.
Next, run the following command.
ssh -L 8080:localhost:80 hostname.username.koding.io
Where hostname is the hostname of your VM, and username is your 
Koding username.
After running this command, you&amp;apos;ll simply connect to your VM.. it may 
appear like nothing has happened. But now, like magic, try loading the 
following URL into your browser.
http://localhost:8080/
Just like magic, you can see that your Port 8080 on localhost is 
returning the same thing as:
http://hostname.username.koding.io:80
Awesome! To connect with something like a MySQL Database Client, simply 
create an SSH tunnel with the appropriate Port on the Virtual 
Machine, and any port you&amp;apos;d like for your localhost. Then connect to 
your localhost with your MySQL Client!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Webmin for Koding</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/guides/webmin-for-koding</link>
    <pubDate>"2014-06-24T00:00:00.000Z"</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/guides/webmin-for-koding</guid>
    <author>Mike Spick</author>
    <description>  The Details This guide will cover the installation of Webmin on your Koding Virtual Machine. Webmin is a web-based adminstration tool for Unix based operating systems. 
This tool will allow you to modify and control applications like Apache, and view/modify your MySQL DBs. Webmin also allows you to modify other system tools 
from the web like users, passwords, iptables, log file rotations and more! If you&amp;apos;d like to read more about Webmin, you can check out their website here.
  Downloading and installing Webmin Alright, first thing&amp;apos;s first, we want to add the webmin team&amp;apos;s repo to our apt sources. Run the following command to open apt&amp;apos;s source list for editing.
sudo vi /etc/apt/sources.list
Press i to enter the vi input mode to edit the list. Add the following to the bottom of the file.
deb http://download.webmin.com/download/repository sarge contrib
It should look like below when you are done.

After adding this line press ESC to exit input mode. Then type :wq to write(save) and quit the file.
Now that apt has the source, lets run the following command to download and install the key needed for webmin.
wget -q http://www.webmin.com/jcameron-key.asc -O- | sudo apt-key add -
We can now update apt, and install Webmin. You can use the following commands.
sudo apt-get update

sudo apt-get install webmin
You will be prompted if you want to continue, press Y to accept.
Once the install is complete, you will see the following as the final output:

Make note of the url given here as you will need it to access Webmin once it is setup.
  Configuration Congratulations! Webmin is now installed on your Koding VM. We only have a few things left to do before it is useable. We need to change the SSL setting in the miniserv config file from 1 to 0. Enter the following command to open the config file for editing.
sudo vim /etc/webmin/miniserv.conf
Once the file is open press i to enter input mode. Use the arrow keys to navigate to the line SSL=1 change this line to read SSL=0. Again, hit ESC and type :wq to write(save) and quit the file.
The file should look like below before editing. 

In order to apply the changes we have made to the configuration, we will need to restart the webmin service. To do that enter the following command.
sudo service webmin restart
You&amp;apos;ve done it! Webmin is installend and configured!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>What is Koding?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/what-is-koding</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/what-is-koding</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>Koding is a robust and feature rich cloud-based development environment complete with free VMs, an attractive IDE and sudo level terminal access. Your ideal software development playground!
The Koding platform provides all you need to move your software development to the cloud. You will be up and running in minutes on your own cloud-based Linux boxes where you can learn programming languages like Ruby, Go, Java, NodeJS, PHP, C, C++, Perl, Python&amp;#x2026;the list goes on! You can experiment with installing, configuring/hacking Wordpress, Laravel, Django, Bootstrap and a slew of others or fire up a MySQL, Mongo, or Postgres server with the click of a button. If clicking buttons is not your thing (yes, we are that way too!) then you also have your favorite vim and emacs right there.
Our collaboration features allow you to pair-program with your friends and colleagues by allowing you to share (in real-time) your web-based IDE, Terminal and white board. All Koding virtual machines come with full root access so you are not hindered in any way.
Signing up is easy and free! Leave your localhost behind and step into the future. Code in the cloud!
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>How do I ask for support?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/support</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/support</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>If your question is not answered on Koding University, feel free to send us a support request.
Because we process a large volume of inbound emails every day, it may take us a few hours before we get to your message but we will get to it within 24 hours. 
In the meantime, here are a few resources that may be helpful: 

The Koding Activity Feed (in case others are discussing a related issue and have a recommendation)
Requests for new guides can be sent here

</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Can I change my Koding username?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/change-username</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/change-username</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>In short no. Why...? It&amp;apos;s because when you first create your account we provision a lot of support services in the background for your account and all of these would need to get updated. This becomes problematic if you have made changes to your VM (even if you have created one file). If you really want to change your username, the only option is to delete your current account and make a new one with the desired username.
But ... you can however , change your display name as seen associated with your the bulletin board posts. Just browse to https://koding.com/Account/Profile where you may change &amp;quot;Name&amp;quot; and/or &amp;quot;LastName&amp;quot; as you would like them to appear to other koding users wherever you chat on koding. This quite niftily has the side-effect of changing your nick on all of you past postings instantaneously. Note that this feature does not in any way allow you to be anonymous. Anyone who clicks on your chat nick (whatever it may be at the time) will always see your canonical username in the URL of your profile.
So to be clear , you may change your display name at any time but this does not affect your login username or VM URL. As stated above that is your system UID and can not be changed.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Should I use my VM's IP or Address?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/vm-ip-vs-address</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/vm-ip-vs-address</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>Koding gives you access to your VMs IP, as well as an Address that 
always points to that VM&amp;apos;s IP, so which should you use, and why?
While your VMs IP will operate perfectly fine, the IP is dynamic. In 
other words, it will change. Because of this, Koding gives you a VM
Address, which will always point to your VM, regardless of 
IP changes, so this is what you usually want to use.
Note: IP addresses of &amp;quot;Always On&amp;quot; VMs don&amp;apos;t change until they are rebooted.
If you have trouble finding your VM Address, click here.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>How can I reset my VM back to it's original state?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/vm-reinit</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/vm-reinit</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>Sometimes, after you&amp;apos;re installed a slew of software and things have started to conflict,
there&amp;apos;s a need to send your VM back to it&amp;apos;s original state. To achieve that, Koding offers
an easy reinitialization function which you can use at any time you like. 
  What does reinitialization do? When you reinit your VM, the system will delete everything on your VM and create a new one from
scratch. NOTE: You will lose all existing data (unless you back it up somewhere) on the VM
that you are reinitializing. This is an irreversible process so please proceed with caution. To backup
your data, we recommend you use FTP 
to transfer the files.
Reinitialization will however preserve your VM settings and any domain names that you may have created.
  How do I reinit my VM? To reinit your VM, follow these easy steps:

turn your VM to &amp;quot;on&amp;quot; state
head over to the VM settings panel (as shown in the screen shot below)
expand the &amp;quot;More&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Advanced&amp;quot; sections
click the &amp;quot;Reinitialize&amp;quot; button inside the Advanced section.

Once you initiate a reinit, you will see appropriate messages on the screen as your VM rebuilds.

</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>How can I delete my account?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/delete-account</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/delete-account</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>You do not have to contact Koding support if you wish to delete your account. Simply head over to Account Settings from where you can easily initiate the deletion process.
It would help us immensly if you can take the quick 3 question survey right after the deletion process ends. It will help us understand why we lost you and how we can improve.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>What ports are open on my Koding VM?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/open-ports</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/open-ports</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>Most Unix ports are available on Koding VMs. We do not block any TCP traffic
(inbound or outbound). See the following list for 
open ports, as well as ports in use by default.

Ports 2 through 65,534 are open.
Port 80 is taken by Apache, but this can be turned off to free up the port. To turn
off Apache, type in: sudo service apache2 stop in Terminal.
Ports 2 through 1,024 require sudo access.

</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>How do turn off my my Koding VM?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/vm-poweroff</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/vm-poweroff</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>To turn off your VM, simply type in sudo poweroff into a Terminal. This will start a graceful shutdown process for your VM and within a few minutes you will see the UI reflect the powered down state for your VM.
A sudo shutdown will shutdown (not power off) a VM...there&amp;apos;s a difference. :)
And a sudo reboot will reboot your machine.  Here is an example of the output after you type in the command:
kodingvm: ~ $ sudo reboot

Broadcast message from kodingvm@kodingvm
kodingvm: ~ $     (/dev/pts/4) at 23:11 ...

The system is going down for reboot NOW!
Wating for a few minutes and then entering CTRL-ALT-T will yield a new terminal in your freshly rebooted machine.
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>What is my VM Hostname/Address/Domain Name?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/vm-hostname</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/vm-hostname</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>The system assigned name for your VM is available on top of the VM settings panel under the label: Assigned URL.
This is not editable.
We realize that most users will probably run into trouble trying to remember our creatively designed VM names 
(sorry, we had to make sure they were unique) so Koding VMs can also very easily be assigned a username based 
namespace (username.koding.io). This makes it easy to remember the domain name for your VM since it is your 
username! (Note: You can still reach the VM by using the system assigned name as described above.)
To assign your username based domain to a VM, follow these 2 easy steps:

open the VM settings panel and click on &amp;quot;More&amp;quot; to reveal the domain settings (as
shown in the image below)
toggle the switch next to your personal namespace to enable it for this VM. (Note: If you have more than one VM, you will be able to reassign the same namespace on other VM settings panels but only one VM can have the namespace applied to it at any given time.)


In addition to this, Koding also allows you to create sub-domains
so that if you want to configure your apache/nginx web server to serve multiple 
virtual hosts, it&amp;apos;s easy to assign them all their own unique sub-domains. Read more about virtual hosts.
To use this feature, head back to the VM settings panel and follow these 3 easy steps:

click the (+) icon next to the &amp;quot;Domains&amp;quot; label to open up an input box where you can type in a new sub-domain. All you need to provide is the sub-domain, we will add the .username.koding.io part automatically.

once added, these sub-domains become available on the setting panels 
of all your VMs for easy reassignment
deleting a sub-domain is as easy as adding one!


</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>How do I transfer/copy files to my VM?</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/transfer-files</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/transfer-files</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>  I want to copy a few files Getting a few files to your Koding VM is simple and there are a variety of methods. We&amp;apos;ve put together a short video titled Importing your files in the Video&amp;apos;s section of Koding University. Check that out for a simple drag-drop method to upload a few files.
  I want to copy a large number of files To copy several files, use FTP. To set up FTP on your VM, simply open up Terminal and type in
help ftp

</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>MySQL Socket Error 2002</title>
    <link>//learn.koding.com/faq/mysql-socket-error-2002</link>
    <pubDate></pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">//learn.koding.com/faq/mysql-socket-error-2002</guid>
    <author></author>
    <description>If you try to use MySQL and receive an error that looks similar to the 
following:
ERROR 2002 (HY000): Can&amp;apos;t connect to local MySQL server through socket 
&amp;apos;/var/run/mysqld/mysqld.sock&amp;apos;
First, make sure MySQL is installed and running on your VM. To install
MySQL, follow this installation guide.
Once you have confirmed that MySQL is installed, start it by running the following 
command:
sudo service mysql start
This should get rid of the Socket Error 2002 error.
If not, send us an email at support@koding.com and we can troubleshoot for you.
</description>
  </item>
  
</channel>
</rss>
